germayne: Hello, hello, hello, everyone.
germayne: Good evening, good evening to everyone.
germayne: You guys can hear me?
AU YANG TAR ben: Yep.
germayne: Good evening, good evening.
germayne: Okay, I think I'll just start… I'll just start in about 1 minute's time, right?
germayne: Okay, so I think… I think to… to… to help you guys…
germayne: follow up with the class. I have also added the slides for today in the shared folder. So it's the same shared folder. I added this slide, so I think if you guys want to take notes during the class, I think it will be easier.
germayne: As well. So yeah, I uploaded. And we have quite a couple of things to… Finish today.
germayne: So…
germayne: Yeah, so I think, I think I… I think giving you guys access to the notes will be… will be super helpful.
germayne: Okay, so I think, I think I will just… I will just start.
germayne: for today.
germayne: Okay, so I think before… before I carry on, so hopefully I can see as many people as possible, so do do… do turn on your camera if you are able, so at least I can… I can look at… I can look at all your faces and at least make the class more interactive.
germayne: Okay, so I think… I think today we have quite a couple of things to go through. So, overall, at a very, very high level, we will be kicking off
germayne: to some of the various different workflows within the data science or machine learning workflow. We'll be talking a bit about things like the evaluation metric, things like how do you process your data, and from the hands-on
germayne: From the hands-on notebook perspective, you will also have the experience to go through the entire data science in terms of training a model.
germayne: you'll be able to go through this example in the notebook, and I think on Thursday, we would then finish up. And again, I know it's not…
germayne: There's not really a lot of time for us to go through so many materials, but you will have a very high-level idea on the various
germayne: mechanism, the various algorithms, as well as how do you actually write it in code, right? And that will actually prepare you guys for the Kaggle exercise that we will be commencing on Saturday.
germayne: Okay, so one… one thing before I… before I… before I really, like, kick off, I made… I made… I made some slight change in terms of the sequencing. So I… I kind of shifted the…
germayne: the theory… sorry, the practical towards the back of the class, so we'll focus a bit on the theory… the theory, the theoretical theory first, and then later on, we will then do the exercise. So I want it to be a bit more…
germayne: coherent, rather than we keep switching, okay? So, soon will be helping me with the notebook, so I'll take some time to cover the theoretical aspect for today.
germayne: Okay, so I'm changing… I'm trying to change a different format so that at least some of the things that I write on the… on the PDF, I will be able to send it to you guys later on. So I'll send two copies, so if today you guys feel like whatever that is written on the PDF, you guys are interested, then I will also upload the same copy. So I'm just trying something different.
germayne: From this perspective.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, thanks, thanks, thanks for letting me know, yeah, okay.
germayne: Okay, so for today, right, we have sort of covered the statistic part from on Tuesday, and on Saturday, I sort of elaborate a bit more in depth, so we'll sort of, like, move away from that.
germayne: that is really more… usually in tech companies, that is usually more from an analytical standpoint, or for an experimentation standpoint. So, moving forward, we'll start to focus more on the machine learning aspect, and if you remember, on Saturday, I sort of told you guys that
germayne: there is this aspect that you come from a paradigm from a computer science perspective. So actually, we are going to focus more towards the computer science perspective, which means more from a machine learning standpoint, and less on the statistical inference.
germayne: So some of you might find it slightly easier, right, and less rigorous in terms of the… the…
germayne: you know, into probability or statistics side of things. 3.2, if you guys remember, we introduced it… we introduced machine learning by giving you guys the introduction to regression model, right? Basically, models that are linear. So today, right, what we will do.
germayne: Is that we will…
germayne: not talk so much about algorithms today. We'll talk a bit about some of the things that you need to consider before you start to apply your machine learning algorithms, okay?
germayne: So, at very high level today, we have a few key objectives, if you look at my screen.
germayne: Okay, radar.
germayne: Okay, so we have, we have four, four, four objectives, but I… I don't think we are able to cover all four of it, so I will move…
germayne: number 4 to Saturday, we'll probably do this on Saturday, but for now, we will focus on the first, second, and third objective. So the first is to really talk about pre-processing.
germayne: your data, this is super important. I think some of you guys sort of ask me, like, oh, how do you actually process your data? And before we even talk about the different algorithms, I mean, I know we introduced the regression models, but
germayne: A very important machine learning workflow is to understand how do you actually
germayne: convert or process your data, and data, there's actually two types of data. You have your numerical data, and you have your categorical data. So, you will see on Saturday, in a practical sense, when I give you guys the Kaggle competition.
germayne: in order to predict the HDB prices, you guys will see that you have 70 over datasets. Some datasets are going to be numerical, right? Things like…
germayne: the size of your house, how high, you know, what is the square feet of the house, what was the number of lease, etc, etc, right? Remaining years.
germayne: Right, those are your numerical data, but most of the time, you also have things like your categorical variables. Things like, oh, what kind of house is it? Is it a 4-room flat? Is it a 5-room resale flat? Is it a mansioner? Etc, et cetera. And…
germayne: A very, a very important part of working with machine learning algorithms is to also know how do you actually handle the processing of these data, because different algorithms have different constraints, if you think about it.
germayne: Right? So some of them allows you to handle, you know, numerical data easily, some of them has challenges with certain categorical variables, and the whole idea here to familiarize yourself is to understand, you know, the different mechanisms to actually process this data.
germayne: Of course, from a cost perspective, we're only going to introduce some of the basic ones, but if you guys are interested, you guys can actually feel free to explore more advanced methods to process your data, and probably I can also talk a bit about it.
germayne: Then, the second thing.
germayne: that we need to discuss, I would say is also very, very important, is the success metrics. So from a machine learning standpoint.
germayne: There's actually… there's actually a… sorry, from a data science standpoint, there's actually two types of metrics that we are always very interested in.
germayne: The first is, as a data scientist, what is the kind of metrics that you can measure from the performance of your model? So basically, this is usually what we call the offline machine learning-based metrics, and these metrics are important because it gives you the importance of
germayne: direction, and it tells you the progress of your models, because you somehow need to be able to measure it, correct? Like, if you were to build a model today, you need to know whether
germayne: is what you are doing, is the data that you have chosen, is the processing that you have done, is the training of the model, does it actually work? So you need some form of metric in order to reason about if
germayne: the model is actually trained correctly if the prediction will work. And that's usually what we call the offline machine learning metrics.
germayne: Of course, in reality, in reality, what will happen is that you have your… you have your offline metrics, this is basically the one that we talk about, right? This is the one where the algorithm basically
germayne: either able to optimize it directly, sometimes it may, sometimes it may not, right? So, the idea here is that you have an offline metrics, but of course, in reality, you have an online metric.
germayne: Right? We are of course not talking about online metric, but does anybody know an example of an online metric in business? So if today, the company were to hire you to build a machine learning model, what kind of online metrics do you think the company would care about?
germayne: Anybody has an idea?
germayne: I see hits.
germayne: turning, but anybody wants to give a shot. Anybody wants to… So, okay, I'll give you guys more context, right? So, offline metrics are basically metrics that will be introduced today. Very, very technical, right? They are technical metrics.
germayne: But what do you think about… what about online metrics?
Zac Ang: Is it, like, how fast it runs?
germayne: That is…
germayne: I think that is still considered a technical metric. That is usually an engineering metric. Actually, you're right. There's actually a third kind of metric, typically, but again, this depends on the workflow. But then there's also, like, the engineering-related metrics.
germayne: Basically, what is the latency for the model? And this is, of course, important if your app
germayne: has some kind of real-time inference, then you need to measure that. But what about… what about online metric? I'll give you guys a hint. It's more… it's more business.
germayne: is a more business metric that people care about. It's less technical, more business.
germayne: Anybody wants to make a guess.
Kim Meng Phoa: Conversion rate?
germayne: Yeah, fantastic. So basically…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, I was thinking I was saying.
germayne: Basically, all your conversion rate, your revenue, your margin, right, your click-through rate.
germayne: Right? People like, people like, for example, if you're Mark Zuckerberg, you will care things like your click-through rate. Hey, how many people are clicking? Right? If I show the ads, are people clicking on the ads? So usually these are your online metrics, right, that are usually business-related. And usually why we call them an online metric is because we cannot measure them.
germayne: Let's say today, if you were to build a model, you… you know, unless you have some kind of simulated environment, it's very unlikely that you can measure the online metric.
germayne: Right? The online metric has the name suggested, it needs to be derived from an experimentation. So now it ties back to 3.1, right? Hey, why must you do hypothesis testing? Why must you know about all the statistical tests? Because, as I mentioned, you're going to do some kind of A-B testing.
germayne: And you're going to expose a portion of the model that you have built, and you are going to measure some of the business impact. So usually this can only be measured online. Today, our focus is on the offline metric, which is, from a technical data science perspective, even before we know whether the algorithm works.
germayne: and provide business value, you need to know whether it works offline first. In your offline setting, does the model train? Is the model trained correctly? Is the model able to somehow able to make an accurate prediction? So we'll talk a bit about the offline metrics.
germayne: On Thursday, we will expand further about measurement, right? Today, we are just talking about what are the metrics that are available, right? What are their trade-offs. On Thursday, we'll talk about how do you actually perform the validation.
germayne: And all… and all of this revolves around the offline setting, which means today, in your own workflow, you can actually make that kind of measurement. You can go to your team.
germayne: you know, after the POC, you can say that, okay, in terms of offline metrics, I have some… I have some of this performance. And sometimes, in reality, it can be a very good indicator of your model. Sometimes it's correlated to the… to the…
germayne: online metric, sometimes, unfortunately, it's not. So sometimes they can be correlated, sometimes they might not, right? Because, ultimately, what you're measuring sometimes is not the business metric.
germayne: Okay, and then the third part, actually, the end-to-end supervised learning workflow, this is actually more towards
germayne: really the code, right? It's just really more of, like, using, sklearn.
germayne: Oh, wait, sorry, huh?
germayne: So for the last part here, it is really just using sklearn, and you'll just learn a bit about the API, right? You'll specifically see some of the API on using the pipeline, the pipeline, the pipeline API.
germayne: Okay, so that is actually more on the notebook. But before I close this slide, basically the three paradigm you need to think about in terms of machine learning
germayne: in terms of the value, it's actually the offline, the online, and the engineering metrics. Engineering metrics, usually, people talk about latency. If it's a real-time… if it's a real-time machine learning system, people usually will look at, like, the P99,
germayne: Prediction latency, whether if it's
germayne: you know, X number of milliseconds, because
germayne: Again, why is it important? If you think about your app, when you're using the app as a consumer.
germayne: you expect it to be very responsive, you expect it to be very fast. What this means is that if there are some kind of decision behind the app that you're using, be it booking a car, booking a ride, ordering food, you wouldn't want to see the screen turning and then spinning and then, like, telling you, please wait, right? You somehow want the experience to be very smooth.
germayne: So what this means is that if behind the scenes there's a kind of machine learning algorithm that's powering the… the experience, then the engineering metrics needs to be considered.
germayne: Okay? So that's a takeaway for this slide.
germayne: Okay, so we'll start first with the preprocessing techniques.
germayne: So, typically, again, if you guys remember what Shumin actually mentioned last week to you guys, is that
germayne: When we think about the entire data science lifecycle, right, if you think about the data science lifecycle, when you first get your data, usually you start to do a problem formulation.
germayne: Essentially, am I able to solve this problem using machine learning, right? Oh, sorry.
germayne: And then what you will then do.
germayne: After that, is you will start to do your EDA, right? To understand more about the data.
germayne: Now, what you want to do is, before you throw it into a machine learning algorithm.
germayne: Here, you can basically see, you need to actually start to do some kind of processing.
germayne: Right? And it should be… it should be intuitive here that
germayne: for EDA and preprocessing, it's actually hand-in-hand.
germayne: Oh.
germayne: Right? It should be intuitive that when you do EDA, and how you should be preprocessing the data, it should be actually related. You shouldn't be knowing what to preprocess without doing the EDA.
germayne: Okay? Because you need to understand the kind of data that you have, you need to understand if there's some issues with the data before you also think about preprocessing it.
germayne: Okay Okay, so essentially, you can see this preprocessing flow. I'm not exactly sure
germayne: I wouldn't, like, 100% agree completely with this, right? Because here, the preprocessing workflow basically is just telling you that, oh, the moment you look at your raw data, you check for missing value, and then you immediately do this. This is… this is actually not… not very true, right?
germayne: in… in… if you are working in a big tech company, of course, you can have the ability to drop data, right? If you have tons of data, you can choose to drop it if it's missing. Why… why… why, you know, try to make some guesses? But if, let's say, you are in a Kagger competition, right, hypothetically.
germayne: you are only given a finite… sorry, you are even given a finite number of data set, that you have some kind of constraint. Then you can think about how to actually impute the data, but
germayne: Again, right, the caveat here is that when you want to impair your data, you have to do some EDA to understand, right? For example, if, let's say, given, you know, a bunch of resale data.
germayne: And you notice that there are some missing value.
germayne: maybe what you can do is you can do some kind of EDA to understand if it makes sense to actually impute the data using your understanding of the data. Hey, maybe if you look at the housing price, for example, a categorical variable that's missing.
germayne: You do not know whether it's 4-room or 5-room. Maybe one way to do it is to look at the EDA,
germayne: understand around the gamerhood, have some kind of domain knowledge, look at the square feet, maybe that allows you to actually fill in the missing values. But the idea here is that you should not be… it shouldn't be like a checklist here, where immediately when I check for missing value, I just impute it.
germayne: Right, it shouldn't be that, it shouldn't be that. And I think I sort of mentioned to you guys during the project, right, that a lot of times you need to really understand your data, you need to be able to know the intuition on what to do. So, I don't really agree completely with this, but I think here it's just basically telling you, from a workflow perspective.
germayne: Right? How… what are the different methods to handle missing data? And if it's a categorical variable, you need to do some kind of encoding. If it's a kind of numerical variable, you might need to do some kind of scaling, right? Of course, of course, again.
germayne: the takeaway from here is that it shouldn't be like a… like a… like a checklist where, okay, if I got numerical data, I just scale.
germayne: Because you need to know why you are scaling.
germayne: Right? And probably I'll give you guys a bit more insights later on. We'll link back to 3.2. You know, if you guys remember, we talked about linear regression, we talked about k-nearest neighbor. I'll give you guys some kind of intuition. But idea is that
germayne: If you go to an interview, you say that, okay, I'm going to scale this data.
germayne: and the interviewer asks you why. You need to be able to know why, right? It can't be that, oh, my lecturer say that if there's numerical, it scales. You guys get what I mean? And I'm not saying that. But for categorical variable, it does make sense, because
germayne: If, let's say, your data has, like, the housing type, 5-room, sorry.
germayne: Let me, let me tap
germayne: So let's say if you… let's say, example, you have some kind of data, the data is basically 5… 5… oh, no, maybe not 5 rooms, let me think of another example.
germayne: Okay, okay, sorry. So maybe, let's say you have the 5-room, 4 room, etc, etc, and then you have your mentioner, you have your lender, whatever. Essentially, you realize that all of these categorical variable.
germayne: Depending on the machine learning algorithm that you want to use, it might not be able to process the… and most of them won't be able to process categorical variables directly.
germayne: Correct? But you know that actually these information are very, very important, right, for the resale flat example. So…
germayne: Normally, you need to… you need to think of some way to encode it. Basically, encode just basically means, like, how do I map from a string space? How do I map it into some kind of continuous variable?
germayne: Or some kind of, numerical variable, because most of the algorithms can only take in Numerical variables. Correct.
germayne: So, categorical variable, yes, you definitely have to encode. I would say most of the time, 100% of the time. Numerical, you need to know why you need to scale, right? For missing value, this is the largest trap, okay? There are many…
germayne: you know, people are always trying to invent ways to handle this missing value, but I would say, right, the gold standard, or the best rule of thumb is.
germayne: If you have access to a lot of data, just drop it, right? But if not, then be a bit careful of what you are introducing, okay? Because if you're introducing garbage, then you're basically just
germayne: sort of, like, polluting the data. I think that's the takeaway here for the missing value.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: So for preprocessing, these are the very, very basic methodology that we will introduce. We'll talk a bit about the categorical variable, how do we actually map? Essentially, what we are doing here is we are just trying to do a mapping. We think of it mathematically as a mapping.
germayne: Right? We are just trying to find a mapping to map from categorical variable space, we are just going to map it to numerical variable, right? And the rationale for this is because a lot of machine learning algorithms, or I would say most of it, actually, most of it.
germayne: They actually cannot understand, text.
germayne: Right.
germayne: models don't really understand text. They are all math.
germayne: under the hood, there's some kind of optimization process that is done. Later on, you will see we will introduce gradient descent, for example.
germayne: Right? Gradient descent, for example, requires the loss function to be differentiable. How can you differentiate something that is not numerical, right? So essentially, all your inputs
germayne: that contributes to the loss needs to be numerical. So that's a reason why we are going to introduce the categorical. But again, there are many advanced categorical variable
germayne: for the mapping, right? These are very, very basic ones. There are things like…
germayne: mean encoding, there's things like, you know, using embedding layer in your neural network to do that. We'll talk a bit more about that, perhaps, later on, right, in later part of the courses. But these are the two basic, basic ones, and this is basically an introduction to what you can encode.
germayne: Okay, then for numerical variable, we will then also introduce
germayne: you know, scaling. We'll talk a bit about why do you need to… we'll talk about what are the different scaling. I'll share the intuition on why do you need to scale. We'll talk a bit about normalization. Not really very important right now, but this is perhaps more important when you move towards deep learning.
germayne: and NLP, and I think the last will be handling missing value. We can just talk a bit about that.
germayne: Okay, so if you… if you look into the tree map, you basically see that, you know, it's just a very straightforward decision mapping here, right? If it has categorical variable, you basically need to encode it. We're going to introduce label encoding, we are going to introduce one-hot encoding.
germayne: And then for your numerical variable, we are going to introduce the standardization. Who remembers what standardization is? Anybody remembers.
germayne: Or is it the first time you heard standardization?
germayne: Anybody knows? What is standardization here?
germayne: Does this sound familiar? Or is it the first time that you are listening to this?
Zac Ang: Is it the Z scaling thing?
germayne: Yes, exactly, exactly. So you see that the formula is exactly the same.
germayne: Basically, minus the mean divided by the standard deviation.
germayne: Okay? So, you see, it's a repeat. You know, and the thing… the funny thing is that in machine learning, right, you will start to see things to be repeated all over the place. So, it's a good thing, like, if you think about it, right? If your foundation is the same.
germayne: then essentially it's the same thing. So, like what Zach mentioned, if you guys remember, we talked a bit about the whole formula on, you know, on 3.1. We were doing the X minus mu.
germayne: divided by your sigma, right? We were… we were sort of doing this, if you remember, we were sort of doing this. So, you'll see, you will see that this is actually your standardization.
germayne: We will also introduce min-max scaling.
germayne: Right? Like, how do you actually scale your data between 0 and 1?
germayne: And the good news is that all of this actually comes from one single library, right? Basically, your scikit-learn library. Scikit-learn has all of these methods, so it's a really great introduction for you to actually apply all of these within your machine learning pipeline.
germayne: Okay, I'll pause here first, before I go on. Anybody got any questions for me?
Chieh Cheng Lai: So, sorry, can you repeat again? Just how you mentioned the standardizations is coming for scaling, it's because on the formula you have written here, X minus mu divided pi is standard d-
Chieh Cheng Lai: Extended, division.
germayne: Correct, correct.
germayne: It's the same formula. If you remember, in the z-score.
germayne: the Z score scaling, if you remember.
germayne: It's the same formula.
Chieh Cheng Lai: This is one of them, or… There's others as well.
germayne: Scaling… scaling, this is the most common one, because here you are trying to center it to 0, mean 0, and standard deviation of 1.
germayne: So it's a very, very common method to scale data.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Okay, so this is one of them, but it's common. Alright, understood.
germayne: Scaling don't have too much option lah, to be honest. Scaling… scaling is usually quite standardized.
germayne: Right? But what I'm saying there has a lot of different methods is actually this.
germayne: This, this portion here.
germayne: Oh.
germayne: Okay, the AI thing is really quite annoying. Okay, but…
germayne: Right? What I'm talking about, the multiple option is actually this, but for scaling, it's actually quite standardized. Like, most people always… if, let's say, you want to do some kind of normalization or scaling, usually you do this scaling. This is quite… this is quite common.
germayne: So there's no advanced or, you know, basic method. This is actually quite common, because
germayne: for a lot of properties, you want to do this kind of scaling because it sort of reduces the value such that the average of this value is 0, and the standard deviation is actually 1. So this is a very common way to normalize data.
germayne: Okay, if that makes sense.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Okay, I understand. Thanks.
germayne: Okay, so I believe Zach actually asked on Saturday, right? Like, oh, hey, you know, if I have categorical variable, how do I actually handle… how do I actually handle the data processing? If Zach, if you remember, right?
Zac Ang: Yes, yeah.
germayne: Where are… wait, wait, sorry, sorry, where are…
germayne: I'm trying to… Minimize my zoom.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so if you, if you, if you, okay, this is one… okay, so if you, if you, if you remember, we sort of talked about it. I mean, I, I talk at a very, very, right, I talk at a very high level about…
germayne: converting the categorical variable into, like, dummy… okay, basically I call it dummy variable, but essentially the alias for one-hawk encoding is actually to dummy… to create dummy variables, it's the same thing. But the idea here is that, if you can see.
germayne: I essentially have a dataset here on the left-hand side. You can see that the first column is actually a column that has
germayne: three distinct values, right? I have blue, I have red, I have green.
germayne: So what I can do is, instead of passing this dataset directly into a machine learning model, let's say in the case that you guys have been exposed to, it's a regression model, you realize that this doesn't make sense, right? Fortunately, a lot of… a lot of libraries, I think if you use some of the stats.
germayne: stats library, they will automatically handle it with you. But under the hood, how they are actually handling this is that they convert them into what we call dummy variables. And essentially, it's the same
germayne: is the same thing as one-hot encoding. The idea here is that I can convert these categorical variables into dummy variables. So, essentially, what you can see is
germayne: from one single column that is my favorite color, I essentially created three columns, right? The three columns would be a column that has blue.
germayne: whether it's blue or not. So if you can see the first column, for the first instance, which is the first row, is actually blue, right? So then, basically, what we just converted is, we created a column that says blue, we say that it's an indicator of 1, red is 0, green is 0.
germayne: Now, for the second instance, because it's red, essentially blue will be 0, red will be 1, green will be 0. So basically what we do is we created a dummy variable where essentially each of the categorical… each of its unique categories becomes a specific column.
germayne: And each of these columns, we now have binary information of whether it's yes or no. So if you guys remember, the example that I gave on… if you guys remember, right, the example for the logistic regression that I gave on gender, you now have male plus female.
germayne: If you guys remember, sorry, male, common, female. So essentially, what we converted was the same thing, right? Instead of each row having a specific category of whether you are male or female, essentially, we just convert them into male equals to 0. If you are male, essentially the indicator for the male column will be 1.
germayne: If you're female, the female column will be 0.
germayne: Okay? Yes, Zach?
Zac Ang: So, the HDB got 27 towns, so if I were to convert the town, I would have 27 rows, columns.
germayne: Exactly, exactly, exactly. So, I'm about to go there. So, obviously, now you guys can start to see, this is a very simple matter. Obviously, linear regression
germayne: linear regression, from a methodology standpoint, it actually, you know, if you go through, like, all the statistic stuff, right, they actually always use one-hot encoding, because it makes sense for linear regression. But of course, if you start to use other models.
germayne: you can start to see that we can use other kind of encoding, but usually for linear regression, or any kind of regression model, usually the preferred way is to do one-hot encoding. Now, I'm going to go to the… I'm going to talk a bit about it, right, and I think these are some of the important key points that you need to take note.
germayne: So, has what you guys mentioned out, you start to realize that
germayne: the… so what we actually… there's this thing that we call the cardinality. So essentially, we know when people say the cardinality, right? So this is the word that I'm saying, so cardinality.
germayne: So the cardinality is basically…
germayne: the… if you think about it from a dimension space, it's really the number of unique values in your categorical variable, right? So if your… if your categorical variable has a lot of unique values, then the cardinality is very high.
germayne: And what happens is that if you were to convert to one-hot encoding, you start to realize that the number of output that you generated scales with the cardinality, and that's a bad thing, because now you are actually increasing the dimension, right? I'll give you another extreme example. Think something like poster code.
germayne: there are a lot of postal code, right? If I were to do one-hour encoding for postal code, and postal code is actually very powerful.
germayne: Correct?
germayne: Do you guys agree with me? If, let's say, you want to do some kind of analysis in Singapore.
germayne: Will you feel like postal code is actually very important? Because it encodes information about where people are staying.
germayne: So postal code is very strong, right? But if, let's say, you're just going to do one-hawk encoding, you realize that your cardinal space becomes very, very, very big.
germayne: And the drawback is that this actually expands the number of columns you have, which is a bad thing, basically. Basically, you are increasing your dimension space upwards.
germayne: And typically, you don't want to have high dimension.
germayne: So that's a drawback.
germayne: Right? So, I think that that's what you guys saw. So, I think it depends.
germayne: There are some cases that… and also, there are some algorithms that don't really…
germayne: you know, enjoy this kind of high dimension encoding. But there are some algorithms that is okay with it, but usually it's quite empirical. From a theoretical standpoint, it makes sense, but…
germayne: I cannot tell you guys when to do it or when you do not do it, because I have personally experienced a specific Kaggle competition that I did, I think, many, many years ago.
germayne: Theoretically, you're not supposed to be using one-hot encoding for a specific algorithm, but it turns out that doing that actually
germayne: Cause the result to be better.
germayne: Right? So the takeaway from here… the first thing, right, I want to share two things on one-haul encoding. The first thing is… the takeaway from here is that the drawback of one-haul encoding is that it increased the dimension space.
germayne: Alright? And…
germayne: Again, the reason it increased the dimension space is because it depends on the cardinality of your categorical variable. If your categorical variable has a lot, right, I think personally, I think, Zach, the example you gave is still okay.
germayne: If, let's say, there are, like.
germayne: thousands of unique columns. You can imagine you are just growing your feature space by a thousand, and that's usually a bad thing, right? We can talk a bit more about the dimensional problem next time. I can share more about the dimensional problem.
germayne: Which is why, in data science, people also have another method to reduce dimension space, but we're not going to talk about that today, right? But the idea is, usually there are methods to reduce dimension, so you can see here that if I'm actually purely just doing one-haul encoding on every single categorical variable, you're going to end up with
germayne: your feature length is going to be very long, which means the dimension is now very high. Okay? I'm not going to talk to you guys so much about why it is it bad, we can talk about it maybe on Saturday or in future.
germayne: But the idea is that, if you guys remember so far.
germayne: Oh.
germayne: If you guys remember so far, whatever that we have basically thought, right, even in linear regression, is we always operate on this curve.
germayne: So, can somebody tell me how many dimensions is this?
germayne: How many dimensions is this?
Chieh Cheng Lai: dimension.
germayne: two-dimension, right? So how does it look like when it's three-dimension? It becomes like that, right?
germayne: You guys, you guys can imagine, right, three-dimension becomes like that.
Hitesh shah: Yeah.
germayne: Right? Anybody can see 4 dimension and above?
germayne: Any, any students here can see four-dimension. If you can, please let me know.
germayne: Okay? So, basically, the idea here is that when your dimension becomes N, right, so let's say… I think, Zach, just now your example was what, 12, is it? Hey, by the way, right, how do you know about the data set that I have?
Zac Ang: You've seen HTV, what, last time?
germayne: Oh, okay. No, but I haven't released the access to anyone yet.
germayne: Okay, bye.
Zac Ang: 27th.
germayne: Okay, correct, okay. So, how many, how many, how many for the example that you have?
Zac Ang: 27?
germayne: Okay, so if you can imagine, right, 27, basically, purely, right, if you're just looking at that one dimension, that one categorical variable, we'll just expand the dimension to 27.
germayne: Of course, as human beings, we cannot… we cannot imagine anything more than 3, right? But there's going to be a problem when your dimension is very high, right? I'm not going to share why, but you just imagine that it's a bad thing.
germayne: So the takeaway for one-haul encoding is that the drawback is that, obviously, here you can see that the cardinality is affecting the number of output, and which is why
germayne: People do come up with… we are going to introduce one more method, but there's obviously other methods that
germayne: Don't have to, you know, that we don't have to have this trade-off of expanding your features to multiple dimensions.
germayne: But the takeaway, again, right? Again, the takeaway for you guys to walk away is that even though one-haul encoding has a lot of problems, it is still widely used, even in deep learning, right? In other neural networks, they still use one-haul encoding, even though it expands a dimension to a wide space.
germayne: Right? People still use it, so it's not like it's useless. It's very much still, being used by everyone, right? But the hard part, again, is you have to try it empirically sometimes, even though, theoretically, it doesn't make sense.
germayne: Okay, I don't want to spend too much time here, already one hour. At this rate, I'm not even sure whether we can go to the practical side, but the takeaway here, right, one last thing, right, for you guys to take away with, is that if you were to do one-hot encoding for your linear regression.
germayne: remember to always drop one, drop one column. So if you guys remember, if you guys remember, again, right, in the example I gave on Saturday about logistic regression, do you guys realize that we actually don't have a variable that is male? Do you guys remember?
germayne: We only had a column that has
germayne: Female equals to 1, and female equals to 0.
germayne: Before I tell you guys the answer, anybody wants to make a guess why mail is actually removed? Anybody knows why?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: by Nore If it's not female, then it's maybe male already.
germayne: Exactly, exactly. So you guys get the intuition, right? So essentially, what we are basically saying is that one of the columns is redundant in information agreed?
germayne: In this… in this example, even for this example, right, even for all the examples, you realize, right, let's say for this.
germayne: In this case, there's red, there's… sorry, there's blue, there's red, there's green.
germayne: If I know that it is not red and not green, it must be blue. Agreed? So you start to notice that actually for all the dummy variables, right, one of the columns is always redundant, and that's what we call the reference group.
germayne: So this is super, super important. And if you remember, one of the assumptions for linear regression is what? No multi-collinearity, right?
germayne: So essentially, you can see that when you create a dummy variable using one-haul encoding, especially for linear regression, one of the columns is actually… you can use all the other columns to predict one column.
germayne: So, which means that one of a column is actually useless. And that's usually what we call the reference column. So, usually people drop.
germayne: people, before they pass into linear regression, they actually drop one of the columns. Because the idea is that
germayne: all the… so it's basically N-1, by the way, so it's N… N minus… n minus 1.
germayne: So, in this example.
germayne: In this example, I have three. I need to drop one so that I have 2 remaining columns. If I have a gender, I have 2 columns. 2, sorry, two, the cardinality is 2.
germayne: I just need to drop one so that I have one column. Okay? So that's a takeaway here. Super, super important for linear regression, or any regression. And you will see all the textbook, every example, everybody always works on a reference.
germayne: Column to drop, I think that depends on you. There's no… there's no answer here. If it's predictive, it doesn't matter.
germayne: If not, you might want to do… again, if you go back to statistical inference, it depends on what you want to infer, correct?
germayne: So, on Saturday, we… I mean, it doesn't really matter lah, because we do have a variable, but you can also interpret from mail. It's not, like, you cannot interpret from mail, so it doesn't really matter.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, I think I need to move a bit faster.
germayne: Okay, so essentially, yeah, you can see here the drawback here is on high-dimensional space, so it's a known… it's a known drawback for…
germayne: One hot encoding.
germayne: Okay? Later on, you'll see tree-based model. Tree-based model, also don't really enjoy one-hord encoding.
germayne: Okay, so we'll talk a bit about the next one.
germayne: Wait
germayne: Okay, so we'll talk a bit about label encoding. So labor encoding is an alternate method where we basically map, it's a direct mapping.
germayne: Basically, instead of mapping
germayne: data into the binary values and creating additional columns, what we are doing is that we are basically just mapping the data one-to-one, where every unique category gets maps into a number, a numerical number. And you can see here.
germayne: blue is basically mapped to 0, green is basically mapped to 1, sorry, red is mapped to 1, and green is mapped to 2, okay? And you can… and you can basically see, right, what you are essentially introducing, right, has a… has a… has a consequence of doing…
germayne: the label encoding is that you're indirectly mapping some kind of ordinal value here. You're indirectly saying that green is actually better than blue, because if you look at the value, you're basically creating some kind of ordering, right, implicitly. You're basically saying.
germayne: You're basically saying that, oh, You're basically saying that green must be more than red?
germayne: I need to learn how to disable this man.
germayne: Okay, so basically we are saying that green is more than red, and red is actually more than blue, if you look at… if you look at… if you look at this mapping, right? So the drawback here is that if you are… if you are using label encoding, you're indirectly introducing some kind of…
germayne: ordinal sorting, where we are actually saying that green is actually, you know, your categories now actually have some kind of specific order. Of course, if, let's say for your data set, right, let's say, for example, let me give you an example,
germayne: not giving you guys any answer for the HDB. If, let's say, for example, things like your 5-room flat, 4-room flat landed, actually, if you think about it from a domain perspective, there's actually some kind of ordering, correct? So then maybe it makes sense to use something like labour encoding, because
germayne: actually, I can map a higher label, a higher label for some of the larger houses, right? Of course, again, this depends on the domain.
germayne: So the good point about label encoding is that, of course, you can see that it doesn't grow the data into a higher dimension. You're not introducing additional columns, right? You also maintain the distribution. If the distribution of green is the
germayne: the highest. Then you can basically, if you were to plot out the distribution for your value tool, you'll see that the distribution is maintained. So, fantastic, distribution is maintained. And some algorithms actually love this, right? For example, if you look at your tree models later on, which we will be talking about on Thursday.
germayne: Because three models, they split. They do splittings on the unique value. You can see that, you know, they… you know, theoretically, it works very well for splitting the data set if you were to do labor encoding.
germayne: And I think for a lot of algorithms, the default is that they will do some label encoding for you, okay? So, yeah, so actually this will be useful if you do not want to hinder your cardinality.
germayne: And of course, the drawback… what do you think the drawback is? The drawback, of course, is that you are introducing some kind of ordering, and if the ordering actually doesn't make sense, it's actually…
germayne: you know, bad for the model. And again, label encoding is mostly used for, I think, tree-based model. Linear regression, mostly people still use. Again, if your data set do have some kind of natural ordering that makes sense, then I think linear regression makes sense. If not otherwise, the interpretation will be nonsense, right, if you try to interpret it.
Hitesh shah: Can we, put ABC instead of 0, 1, 2, 3, or…
germayne: No, you can't, you can't, you can't. You need it to be numerical. You need it to be numerical, yeah.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Sorry, so, so, label encoding is not suitable for use for the regression. The regression have to use one hot encoding.
germayne: Theoretically, yes, but as I mentioned, the whole idea of encoding data, right, is so that you preserve the signal. If, let's say, again, for your context, let's say in HDB,
germayne: let's say one of our data sets is the story, right? What's the story? Story… story is in terms of how high the flat is. If it says 13, level 13, I'm mapping it to 13. It's correct, right?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Hmm.
germayne: It's not that it's wrong. So…
Chieh Cheng Lai: Oh, it's.
germayne: So it depends, right? So the takeaway is, it depends. If, let's say, for example, you have another one, like, maybe landed.
germayne: Condo, 5-room, 4-room, whatever.
germayne: Right? Historically, historically, right? Or rather, from a domain perspective, most of the landed must be bigger than 3-room flat. There's no way the landed is smaller than 3-room flat, right? So if you were to use some kind of ordinal mapping, then naturally, it makes sense.
germayne: Even for linear regression.
germayne: And again, this is for the predictive standpoint, for statistical inference, the interpretation might not make sense if your dataset is using label encoding.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Okay?
germayne: Okay, all good, right?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Historic.
germayne: Okay, so essentially, these are all how do we actually handle the categorical variable. Of course, there are many, many other methods, right? There are many other methods. I would encourage you guys to go and read up on what are the different methods, and…
germayne: If you've got any eyes, got any questions, we can discuss, okay?
germayne: Okay, so I'm just… I'm just going to move a bit forward. So, okay, so now we are going on to how to actually process your… your…
germayne: numerical data, right? So, essentially, for numerical data, there's only either scaling or handling missing data, right? Just these two types of transformation. So…
germayne: Anybody wants to make a guess, why do you actually want to scale your data? Anybody actually knows about this before I go on. Anybody knows why, actually, we need to scale.
germayne: Any intuition?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: So you don't need to handle things that go infinity.
germayne: Any example you are thinking about?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Dollar value, if, let's say, a dollar transaction.
germayne: Hmm.
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: You know, you buy something, it can be very cheap, and…
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: If that… the basket analysis does not,
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: have some form of categorizing the dollar value. It might be…
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Then, when you measure… when you try to measure the basket itself, you have.
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: very large skewer.
germayne: I see. Okay. Actually, also not wrong. So, so basically, right, if you think about scaling data, I believe, right, even if you are not introduced to machine learning.
germayne: even if you want to do analysis, right? Scaling data, I think, is also quite natural for a lot of, like, analysis that perhaps a lot of you guys do, from an analysis standpoint. Maybe you are interested to make some kind of comparison across your dataset, right? Maybe, without even talking about machine learning.
germayne: people might really think about scaling, right? Because, hey, maybe I got 3 different data, the units are all different, maybe I need to scale them so that I can compare them, right? This makes perfect sense.
germayne: Today, right, what we want to talk about specifically is why do we want to scale so that we can… what kind of property we want to… that we want to sort of encode, right, into your data, so that the machine learning algorithm can handle, okay? So we'll talk about the min-max scaling and the standardized scaling.
germayne: Right? And what is the consequence of that?
germayne: But I think Philippe is also correct, that there are also cases that you might want to just scale your… I mean, scaling is not scientifically new, right? You're just basically normalizing the data so that it's just between 0 and 1, especially for min-max scaling, right? And you can actually do this across each of your independent data. If I have, F1, I have, F…
germayne: if I have F2, right? Essentially, maybe if I want to have some kind of comparison, right.
germayne: I might want to scale them, because otherwise, if they have differences in unit, might not be interpretable. Same thing for your standardized scaling, right? Standardized scaling, if you notice, if you scale your data here, your interpretation will change, because each of your units now becomes comparable. If I were to apply both of these scaling to
germayne: Column 1 and column 2.
germayne: Min-max scaling basically allows them to be in the same range, right? They're always bounded between 0 and 1. 0 to be the minimum, 1 to be the maximum, right? So I can have some kind of comparison between two of them.
germayne: Standard scaling actually has a similar idea. If I'm scaling
germayne: Your column 1, your variable 1, and your variable 2.
germayne: The beauty is that now they are on… they're operating on the same scale unit.
germayne: If F is KG,
germayne: Okay.
germayne: I'm so sorry.
germayne: I think I need to figure out how to make this better, okay? But if, let's say, F, right.
Josiah Ho: Jermaine, the next time the message come out, I think you can tick a box there that says.
germayne: Oh, see, Repta.
Josiah Ho: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, okay, where make the box.
germayne: No, it's not appearing, though.
germayne: Okay, I think when they appear, I keep checking it off. You guys can see the box coming out, is it?
germayne: Or, no. You guys can see lah. Okay, maybe I'll check it, I'll check it later. But thanks, thanks. Thanks for the tip. Okay, so, right, okay, so back to what I was saying. So for standard scaling, right, if let's say, your first column is something like kg.
germayne: And your second… second column is something like CM.
germayne: Or maybe if your third column is something like, in terms of time.
germayne: Then you realize that each of your variables is all in different units, and you cannot reason with them. So, scaling, right, either, both scaling, actually sort of bring them to the same unit, because if it's 0 and 1, basically you're just talking about the maximum and minimum of this… within its own range. Standard scaling.
germayne: basically, if you look at the formula, right, if you look at the formula, we are… we are reducing the mean divided by the standard deviation. So actually, now we are talking about in terms of the standard deviation from the mean. So if, let's say, you have some value here, let's say the X bar becomes 5,
germayne: 5, right? Then, essentially, we are saying that, oh, it's actually 5 units away, you know, in terms of standard deviation, away from the mean. And the beauty of this is that now if your data set has different
germayne: interpretation, in terms of the unit. All of them actually becomes, in terms of the deviation
germayne: with respect to the mean. So all of them becomes the same unit. But of course, the interpretation may not make sense, but it allows them… allows you to compare them, right? In Module 1, if you are doing something like visualization sometimes, of course, if the… if the unit… and maybe, let's say, for example, you have another unit that is…
germayne: In terms of, like, dollar.
germayne: and you want to do some kind of visualization, you'll realize that if the unit is actually very different, your plot will not make sense. So usually people standardize to also fix that, but from a machine learning perspective.
germayne: what you want to take away here is that I want to go back very quickly to the algorithm that you guys actually learned in… I think Xu Min actually talked about KNN.
germayne: Right? I'm not scolding any vulgarities, by the way. I'm saying K nearest neighbor. So KNN, right, if you remember, in a two-dimens space, right, you have all your data set which defines the training data, sort of.
germayne: Right? And what happens is that
germayne: If you have a new data, a new inference data, it's actually measuring the distance between the data set from your… so let's say if you have variable 1,
germayne: You have variable 1, and you have variable…
germayne: Boo.
germayne: Essentially, what we are doing is that we are just finding that specific point, find who's the nearest, and then we try to take a vote to determine the target, the output prediction, right? Has classification or regression.
germayne: Now, what I want to illustrate to this is that if you guys realize the example that I used, imagine your variable 1 is your width, variable 2 is, like, in CM,
germayne: What do you guys think would be your problem?
germayne: What will be a potential problem? Anybody knows.
germayne: If I do it on K&N algorithm.
Zac Ang: It's not comparable.
germayne: Yes, correct? But what is the… what is the dangerous thing that it will cause?
germayne: I mean, so what if it's not comparable? I mean, KNN, you don't need to interpret it, but what do you think would be a problem?
Lim Hung (Lanson): It changes what the model being is similar.
germayne: Huh? Sorry.
Lim Hung (Lanson): It changes what the model thinks is similar.
germayne: Okay, I think, I think, I think roughly, roughly, I think it's the right direction. So essentially, if you think about the scale, right, if you were to do a plot, if you were to do, if you were to do a graph.
germayne: If your data set between the two variables, the scale is very different, you realize that
germayne: Let's say if my dollar is in terms of millions, your unit is, like.
germayne: 5… sorry, your unit is, like, seven zeros. Your KG unit is always two zeros. What will happen? You realize that on the… on the… on the x-axis and the y-axis, one becomes very…
germayne: Expanded, one becomes very contracted.
germayne: And that's a problem for KNN, right, if you can imagine, correct?
germayne: Imagine if my… in my dataset is all in millions.
germayne: And then suddenly you have somebody in thousands. Some is here.
germayne: Some will be here.
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: For wrongly.
germayne: No, it's not about infer wrongly, but you realize that one variable gets skewed all the way, right?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Hmm.
germayne: this variable gets skewed. Very, very, very, very, very, very skewed. So basically, the V2 is actually very skewed. It's actually pulling away everything from V1.
germayne: When they are all different units. So, the problem here is that you want to do this kind of scaling because
germayne: things like KNN, and later on, you will see some of the algorithm in unsupervised. Anything, right, that actually… imagine them on a n-dimension space, you just put the dots, right, and then finding out about the dots, right? Each of the dimensions needs to be in the same unit.
germayne: And that is why we want to do scaling. So things like KNN is a very, very good example.
germayne: Okay, KNN is a super, super good example.
germayne: Okay, I hope you guys get the intuition, huh? So, the intuition here for scaling is usually very useful when you have things that are of different units. It's very useful for visualizing, it's very important for algorithms that think about… and I'm giving this example in two-dimensional space, but of course it applies to n-dimensional space as well.
germayne: if there are variables that are of very big unit, that variable will actually distort the interpretation. It will be very… it will be more concentrated on that variable.
germayne: has compared to the other variables. I mean, it will… it will basically…
germayne: if, let's say, your numbers are in 7 digits, basically anything that is, like, in your KG will just be… it would just be squeezed up, right? You can imagine it would just be meaningless. So basically, I might as well just use variable 2 to just do the separation.
germayne: Because each of the variables from variable 1 does not matter, right? They are also squeezed up.
germayne: Right? So that's the idea for standardized scaling and min-max scaling. Of course, there are many, many reasons why to do standard scaling also, standardized scaling. Neural network, very important for gradient descent.
germayne: Right? We are not gonna… I don't talk too much about it yet. We can come back later. So for your neural network.
germayne: Hey, sorry, let me, let me finish first, let me finish first, sorry, huh?
germayne: Let me finish Raza. So for neural network, very important for your gradient descent, okay? So there are… there are a lot of algorithms that are…
germayne: sort of very sensitive to the data. Gradient descent, very sensitive because
germayne: later on, when I show the math, right, you will see that when we do the chain rule, when you do backpropagation.
germayne: any value that is super, super big actually will result in very small gradient. Where you take the derivative, it will be very small. And you don't want very small gradient, because you want to have the update to be quicker, right? So therefore, you need to do scaling, right? But for KNN, very important.
germayne: Anything with the k-nearest neighbor, k-means, which you will see later on in unsupervised. I'll repeat, I'll again emphasize again, scaling is super important, okay? Of course, later on, it will affect regression, but I'll talk about it separately, perhaps on Thursday.
germayne: Okay, sorry, yes, yes, Hu Hu is asking me for a question?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yeah, I actually, I have a question. I just want to show the two-dimensional variable 1, variable 2. So, okay, so in this case,
Chieh Cheng Lai: For example, a wearable one can be dollar, wearable 2 can be kg. So, only two parameters can be represented in two dimensions. So, if I want to have CM and time, can it represent on the same graph as well, or different graph?
germayne: See… oh, so you want to put all four, is it?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yes, yes.
germayne: Yeah, you can, you can, but it'll be 4 dimension, and I cannot draw 4 dimension out in the class.
germayne: So, I mean, so usually in methodology, we always draw two-dimension, three-dimension, but you just imagine, right, okay, so let's say, let me help you lah, okay? So let's say, for example, you got dollar, KG, you want to put CM,
germayne: Can you imagine this in three dimensions? You can, right? So you'll just be like that.
germayne: Hey, sorry, huh?
germayne: It would just be like that, right?
germayne: There's your V3s at it.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Hmm.
germayne: you can imagine they're just floating in the three-dimensional space, right? So then your K nearest neighbor, the algorithm will still be the same, right? You just plot them in the three-dimension space, you just find out who's a neighbor. So same thing, you can put all four of them four-dimensional, you can put 100 dimension also. K and will work.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Oh, okay, it's just we cannot initialize.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, yeah. So basically, from an intuition perspective.
germayne: you think of it from an understanding of two-dimension, three-dimension, it will be the same to n-dimension, but we don't… we don't imagine the visualization of n-dimension, but the idea is the same. You are just using all of the neighbors.
germayne: And you are just measuring who is the nearest.
germayne: In order to determine the… and the idea is, like, voting like that, right? If I find 3 persons near you, then the idea is you must be the same as these 3 persons.
germayne: So that's actually the idea of Canadian University Neighborhood, right?
germayne: So let's say, let's say, I don't know, you want to make some kind of prediction. You want to predict the income.
germayne: If these 3 person went to the same uni, the 3% scored the same, then our model will say that, oh, actually this person would have the same salary, right? Because the idea is that if it's near this cluster of data points, then it must be the same, it must be similar. So what I'll do is I'll take an average around all of them.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Okay, but, another question is, you say it can be n-dimensional, then in this case, how the model can tell me which one is the… yeah, I mean, we can't visualize, so how the model can, I mean, tell us this group, this one group, the other one is another group?
Chieh Cheng Lai: in… in the KNN, I mean, because right now we cannot visualize.
germayne: you know, it's just… it's just taking all the data points. I mean, the… the… the… the… the… just… just saying, right,
germayne: So, for example, if your matrix, right, Let me draw out.
germayne: No, I mean, we cannot visualize in our head, but mathematically, we can express it.
germayne: You can always express n-dimension with a vector. So if your vector, right, is… 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
germayne: This is 5-dimension already.
germayne: This is 5 dimension,
germayne: This is 5 dimensions. I mean, just that you cannot see it, but we can calculate it, it's not like we cannot.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Okay, so medic… so it will base on some medical… medical calculation.
germayne: Yeah, I mean, for… correct.
germayne: I mean, KNN is just very simple, right? We are just finding the distance. You can calculate distance between any arbitrary vector.
germayne: In no vector, right? This is a vector. I can calculate a distance between this vector and other vector, right?
germayne: I don't need to imagine it, I can calculate it. If I can calculate the distance, I can find who are the similar points that is similar to Xi, right? I can find… I can definitely find X1…
germayne: X5, X10,
germayne: X 1500. I can find the neighbors, mah, right, using the vector. And because if I can find the vector, I can definitely take the average.
germayne: And I can return you the value. That's why I'll go for K, and it's very, very simple.
germayne: But…
germayne: But if your question to everyone else applies to everything, every model uses n dimension. You can calculate it.
germayne: Just that we cannot express it.
germayne: Visually.
germayne: Makes sense, right?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yeah, makes sense, makes sense. Yeah, yeah, I get the idea. Thank you. Okay.
germayne: Okay, I think I'll stop. I'll stop here first. I'll stop here first.
germayne: And we go for a quick break.
germayne: Okay, so for today, right, is it okay if we go for a 5-minute break? We have a few things to cover. Let's go for 5 minutes, okay?
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, let's come back at… 8-11, yeah.
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Sorry to intervene.
germayne: Hmm.
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: The scaling, right, can we actually call it normalization?
germayne: Yes, yes, it's the same, it's the same.
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Okay, gotcha.
germayne: It's the same thing, yeah.
germayne: Just that I think sometimes normalized people also say that this is also, like, normalizing.
germayne: So, yeah.
germayne: I think this is just more… more accurate to the way the library
germayne: I mean, if you want to find a library, if you find Normalize, I think sometimes they might either give you this or this, but yes, Normalize is also the same thing lah.
germayne: Oh.
germayne: Okay, one more minute.
germayne: Okay, I'm sorry, I'm sorry if this feels very rushed, but the materials really just got too many. There's just too many things.
germayne: So… so I'll try to talk about the important things, and then at least you guys still have a chance to at least go through the notebook later.
germayne: And I'll try to skip some stuff that… It's not that important.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, okay, so… yeah, let's, let's, let's get started. Hope you guys had a good toilet break.
germayne: Okay, so I think before I… before I continue on, just one last important thing to talk about, right? So for any of the scaling and the encoding, right, the general idea, right, that you guys need to have and take away is that
germayne: Okay, so…
germayne: Later on, when we start to do the notebook exercise, you'll start to realize that we have this,
germayne: This, this whole idea about the radar.
germayne: We have this whole idea about the train, and the test…
germayne: to split your data, right? We'll talk a bit more about this on Thursday, when we talk about cross-validation, about how do you actually split this. But I want to talk a bit about this because
germayne: Conceptually, right, everything that we are doing in machine learning, whenever we talk about training the model, we're always talking about a bunch of data set for you to prepare the model.
germayne: And that includes preprocessing, okay? So it's not just training the model, it includes preprocessing. And then, conceptually, there's also tests, but if you want it to be a bit more accurate, right, from my perspective, actually, there's actually four… four…
germayne: Pia, sorry.
germayne: there's actually 3 different categories, right, from a perspective. So, I want to talk a bit about this is because
germayne: This actually applies to whatever that I've talked about above.
germayne: whatever that you are doing from a dataset perspective, you're always taking a bunch of data. This is the universe of information, and you know it's a sample. You know it's not everything, right?
germayne: This sample of data is what you want to actually create your model, and your goal is… your… obviously, your goal is to have a model that's very good at doing this, to test it.
germayne: Right? Why do I say so?
germayne: If today, you're building a model, you're preparing this model to apply for all the future users, you're always doing it future, for a future inference, you're always going to use it for a future use case. You are never going to use it on the training.
germayne: very good analogy is training a model is like preparing somebody to go for exam, right? You have a bunch of information, you study your exam, you study your previous notes, you study everything.
germayne: you are only very good at your preparation. But your preparation is not important, right? When you study for your exam, whatever you study for is not important. What is important is your actual… actual exam, right? Your actual O levels, your actual A levels, etc.
germayne: And that's actually in your test.
germayne: We're going to talk a bit about the validation. Validation, you can think of it, right, from a simple analogy, like, before you go for your O-levels, you will actually do a prelim, like, prelim, right, preliminary exam, right? Somebody will let you, like, okay, I think this is our best guess of Cambridge exam.
germayne: Right? You can think of it like a validation. We'll talk a bit about this idea in… on Thursday, but the reason I'm bringing this up first is because when you're standardizing your data.
germayne: One thing to take note is that you are standardizing this per feature. So, if you have 77 data, like, in your Kaggle data that you have on Saturday, if you have 77,
germayne: If you want to do standardizing, you're standardizing them 77 times. Each column has its own standardization, and it makes sense, right? Because you are trying to do the transformation on each column separately, so that they are all onto the same unit.
germayne: Right?
germayne: So now, what this means is that, if you think about it, right, you have the 77 columns, you are doing the standardization, you are calculating two parameters here. Look at the formula. X for all the data set in that one column, so this is for one column,
germayne: Or one column.
germayne: You take the average, which is mu, you divide it by the standard deviation. You're repeating this n number of times for n columns.
germayne: The question here is that when you need to prepare your model for future inference.
germayne: you take the standardized data to train your model, so the expected input to make the prediction is that you need the test data to also be standardized, right? But you cannot calculate this in real time. How can you calculate and standardize this in real time? So what you are doing is, the mu and the sigma comes from your training data.
germayne: Okay?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Sure, so important.
germayne: So, please, please, please keep this in mind. This is super, super important because
germayne: If this theoretical concept you don't understand.
germayne: in the code, right, you will remember, like, oh, your .feed, dot transform, you'll remember that. But I have seen people make mistakes in interview, just to tell you guys. Very memorable, as in one of the early, early couple of years back when I marked one assignment, the candidate made this mistake.
germayne: And basically, I failed I can eat it immediately.
germayne: Because if you're not doing the split properly, you are doing your standardization on your test set, it's wrong, by the way.
germayne: Because in real time, you don't have access to
germayne: Mu and sigma, you can only have it from your train data.
germayne: Same thing for… okay, min-max scaling, yeah, same thing for your min-max scaling, same thing for your standard, standard scaling. Same thing for your labor encoding, because in real time, you might have new labor that you have not seen, but you cannot encode that.
germayne: In real time, right? Same thing for your one-haul encoding.
germayne: If, let's say, today my gender has female.
germayne: Okay, so let's say, right, if my gen… oh, I don't use gender lah, let me, let me use a different one, sorry.
germayne: So let's say again, to drive this idea again, let's say if I color, my training data only has blue.
germayne: Green, and… red.
germayne: And in your tests, right, I'm gonna copy this and paste here.
germayne: Right? And in, in your, in your actual test time, right, if you are, if you are given purple.
germayne: For example, you realize that you cannot encode this. So the encoding, right, the concept here is that the encoding always comes from the train.
germayne: Okay? And if you can… if you can understand this concept, later on when we do the notebook, right, it will be very simple, because the code is not important, the concept, the theory is an important part.
germayne: You will realize that the application for calculating the transformation always comes from the training data, not from the validation, not from the test. Because the idea here is that if you have prepared
germayne: Your knowledge from your… from whatever, from your, you know, your 10-year series, from your… your textbook.
germayne: you can't change that, right? You can't… you can't make the… you can't get information from validation time and test time.
germayne: So if there's purple in one hot encoding, you cannot handle that. You have to think of a different way to handle that. You cannot add another additional column. That makes zero sense.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Important point to take then, so if you have a note to write, make sure you write this down. This is the most important, I would say, the takeaway. And you will start to see this pattern, I believe, later on in your notebook, you will start to see a…
germayne: Just to drive back home the notebook, right? sklearn, this is specifically for sklearn, but it doesn't really matter. If next time there's a new library, the concept will be the same.
germayne: You're always doing a dot feed.
germayne: dot fit basically means I'm going to calculate the steady state using my training data.
germayne: And then for your validation, it's always the dot transform.
germayne: Basically, you're applying what you have calculated to your transformation data. So, essentially, it is storing
germayne: mu and sigma, if you are talking about standardized scaling. It needs to store mu and sigma for every column that you process. It will store it, and that's how it can perform the transformation, okay?
germayne: Okay, I'm going to skip the L2 normalization. We can probably talk about it later when we talk about neural networks, not important now.
germayne: Okay. I think… I think I'll just go very quickly for missing… missing value. I already mentioned it is not completely aligned with my principle, but the idea here is that you can essentially use EDA to understand if you can replace the missing data by taking a mean
germayne: median or mode of the column. But again, this depends, right? This depends. You make sure you do your EDA to see if
germayne: It makes sense to take in the mean, median, or mode, okay?
germayne: best gold standard is if you have the luxury to drop the data, then just drop it. Okay?
germayne: Okay, if you are… if you are… if, let's say, you have 1 million data, you have 50 missing columns, then just drop it. Don't need to waste time on it.
germayne: Okay? But if you, if you, if you unfortunately cannot, then you need to understand whether if imputation actually works.
germayne: some algorithm, which we will discuss on Thursday, they can handle missing value, right? Basically, the algo can just handle missing value as a kind of specific input.
germayne: Okay, but not all models handle missing value. Your neural network definitely cannot. Linear regression also cannot handle missing value.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, so I think we spent some time talking a lot about the preprocessing.
germayne: I think you guys have the clear takeaway, and I hope you guys apply the knowledge
germayne: Especially for the Kaggle.
germayne: Okay, so the next bulk of the class, we'll be just talking about the classification matrix. We'll talk about the classification problem, so this is for classification. I want to remind you guys again, classification basically means if I were to train a model, F ,
germayne: F of X basically predicts Y, right? Basically, a classification problem means that my Y
germayne: We're going to be a probability, so it will be a probability between 0 and 1.
germayne: Okay? And of course, the dataset that you train on will either be 0 or 1.
germayne: Okay? We train the model using a binary data, prediction will be a probability between 0 and 1.
germayne: Okay? And what we want to talk about is classification metrics. How do we know if the model is performing good or bad? We need some kind of
germayne: Metric in order to reason whether it's good or bad.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: We'll introduce a couple of concepts. These are all fundamental concepts that everybody still uses. You still need to use
germayne: confusion matrix. Accuracy, maybe not so much, but precision recall, specificity, and the F1 score, very common metrics. If you read any published papers, they'll usually publish the precision recall. Sometimes they mostly publish the F1 score, right? Sometimes they will publish the accuracy if the data makes sense.
germayne: Okay? But essentially, the idea here is, how do I know if my model is performing better, or performing well? I need some kind of classification metric.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Actually, classification metric, last time we learned about P-tests, T-test, Z test.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Are they also related to this one?
germayne: No, that is not. That is for your statistical inference.
germayne: This is to measure your machine learning model.
germayne: Different.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Okay, okay.
germayne: Zach test, t-test, p-test… actually, they're all different things, by the way. Your t-test, right, gives you the p-value. The p-value is the one that we reason under the curve to do hypothesis testing. Different, huh? That one is… that one, right, to remind you guys again.
germayne: The statistical inference is that we always have a sample of data, we are trying to make some kind of inference to the population.
germayne: That is from the statistical test.
germayne: This classification metrics, right, is you train a machine learning model F of X.
germayne: Okay, and I always call it F of X, it's because you put in X data, X1, X2, X3, you want to predict Y, so it's F of X gives you Y. Now, if I have Y prediction, I have a bunch of labored data, 0 or 1.
germayne: my model is predicting either probability, right, some kind of probability output. How do I know if the model is performing good or bad? And this is important for you to know, because when you build a model.
germayne: Anybody can build a model, but somebody needs to know whether the model works or not.
germayne: So, classification metric is a way for us to measure if the model is working or not. Think of it like a way to assess
germayne: If your model is in the right direction.
germayne: Because…
germayne: in the coming… in the… in the coming example for your Kaggle competition, everybody here in your groups, you guys will be training a model to predict resale prices.
germayne: Correct? But there must be a way to measure whether whose model is the better, whose model is more accurate.
germayne: Right?
germayne: I don't expect.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, sorry. I have a question.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So earlier you talk about the online metrics and the offline metrics.
germayne: Yes, yes.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So what kind of gives an online metrics on the… I mean, let's say I can simulate the model. I got the data, I simulate it.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Can't that be a good enough, metric instead of relying… on top of relying on this one?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, I never thought of the online metric until today, so I was just thinking, the online metrics measure all the revenue and everything, and assuming I've got all the data.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Right, then why can't I, you know,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: you said, instead of, you know, I mean, on top of… I mean, I… maybe… maybe it's not as technical as that, but would that also be give… would that also give a very good sense, or a better sense of whether your model is actually working better?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Seems like…
germayne: So, you make a perfect, you make, you know, your point is right on point. If lah, right, hypothetically, you have a simulated environment to simulate, then of course, the online metric makes sense.
germayne: Right, and there are teams that want to build the simulation, but do you know why simulation and RAM is hard? Because the world is noisy, right?
germayne: The real world is noisy, it's not… it's not controlled, it's not like a system that you can build. But, of course, if you can somehow simulate this, then online metric works.
germayne: But 99%, a lot of people cannot do the simulation.
germayne: Right? A simulation environment is a bit like, let's say, for example, I'll just give you guys some context, right? So let's say today you have a product.
germayne: then you want to understand if these people will buy. Can you simulate it? Sure, you can. If, let's say, you can hypothetically
germayne: build a system that is able to get a very good representation of people's interests. Then you can simulate whether people will buy, right? But how will you know? The only way to know is to release your product so that you know whether people would like it or not.
germayne: That is the idea. But, fair point. And there are companies that have teams that tries to build simulated environments, but that's a separate complexity lah, right? Because you need to then somehow build some kind of simulation to sample the preference from real people.
germayne: Right? So, of course, of course, for the course, right, we're talking about offline first. Offline is the easiest, and you should always use offline metric. Why talk about online when your offline metric is not good? You get what I mean? If your offline is good, right, then we talk about online. If your offline is not even good.
germayne: Man, your model is not good. Why we even talk about whether we can put it in production?
germayne: Correct? So that's the whole idea. Again, right, classification metric is not solely just used for machine learning. You can use confusion metrics for anything that has 0 and 1. Basically, anything that tries to predict whether it's 0 and 1
germayne: You can use the confusion matrix.
germayne: Okay, so if you can see the conversion matrix, alright, conversion matrix basically is a 2x2 grid.
Josiah Ho: Jermaine, are you sharing your screen?
germayne: Oh, sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry. Lucky, lucky. Lucky you guys point out. You know, later, I talk for one hour, then you guys say, hey, actually, you made one hour, your… your slides is not on. Okay, it's only… it's only… it's only… I only just closed it, right, just now, is it correct?
germayne: Okay, okay. Okay, sorry.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, after my question. Yeah, sorry.
germayne: No problem, no problem, because I closed the extra window. Okay, so, okay, so back to the classification metrics, right? So what I was just saying is that this… you will see, right, actually, it's a measurement that makes intuitive sense, not just for machine learning, okay?
germayne: Okay, so a conversion matrix is a… is a… is a… as you guys can see, it's actually… right now, in our example, it's 2x2. It can go more than 2x2, but…
germayne: For now, for now.
germayne: For now, it's just 2x2, okay? So in 2x2, right, example, it's because
germayne: Your target label is 1, if you guys remember.
germayne: This is why.
germayne: Right? I mentioned that… I mentioned that, your prediction is a probability, right? But for now, let's pretend we can convert the probability to 1, to 0 and 1 as well.
germayne: Right? So imagine, right, your… so this is Y hat, by the way, Y hat is always a prediction. So, your prediction value, let's suppose I can convert the probability to
germayne: to 1 and 0. You notice that there's actually going to be 4 outcome here.
germayne: Agree, right? I'll repeat again. Your target label will be
germayne: 1 and 0 binary, right, whether that thing happened or not. Your prediction will be probability, but let's pretend now, at this point in time, you can convert them to 0 and 1.
germayne: And you realize that there's going to be 4 outcomes. It's either going to be, it's 1, you say it's 1, it's 1, you say it's 0. Is 0, you say it's 1, and it's 0, you say it's 0. So it's going to be 4 outcomes.
germayne: And what happens is that you can actually illustrate them in a confusion matrix. Basically, what this means is that you say it's called… you say it's 1,
germayne: And the actual is 1, so that's not called the true positive.
germayne: You can say it's 0, but it's actually 1, then that's actually a false negative.
germayne: Right.
germayne: For the negative side.
germayne: You can see that if it's… you say it's at zero, you predict it at zero, and the actual zero is true negative.
germayne: And of course, for the last one, is that you predicted to be positive, but it's actually negative, so it's actually a false positive.
germayne: So it's just going to be 4 different quadrants.
germayne: And this four quadrants usually allows us to access your model. You know, if let's say, you can convert them to 0 and 1, you can actually basically see
germayne: Of course, from your perspective, I want to ask you guys, what will be the best case scenario? Which quadrant that you want to hit would be the best case scenario here?
germayne: You want to hit the ones in green, right? Everything that is actually 1, you predicted 1. Everything that's actually 0, you predicted 0. So these two, you want it to be the highest value as much as possible. Obviously, you want to minimize the ones that you're making here, right?
germayne: So here you can see, right, by definition.
germayne: A conversion matrix has 4 points. For a binary case, which is for 1 and 0, you're going to have 4 different outcomes.
germayne: You have your true positive, which means the actual case is positive, you predicted correctly.
germayne: U has a true negative, basically cases that are zero, and you predicted zero.
germayne: You have the false positive, basically you say it's positive, but actually it's zero, and the last case is the false negative, right? You say… you say it's negative.
germayne: It predicted negative, but actually it's positive.
germayne: So if you… if you want… if you want to remember this, just basically draw the quadrant out. Then you basically have the four different…
germayne: output. So this allows you to actually, from a baseline level, determine whether if, you know, given something that actually happened, and then whether what you predicted.
germayne: Either from your system, model, from your machine learning model, or for some other cases, you're able to get the confusion matrix.
germayne: And you can see that this is basically just trying to reconcile cases where you put 1, is it 1? Cases where you put 0, if it's 0. So, and you can see that you can actually use a conversion matrix outside of machine learning model as well, right? It's not just machine learning models. You can basically arrive at these to determine some kind of performance.
germayne: Okay, so this is just a fun meme for you guys to go back and see.
germayne: Okay, so for now, right, the takeaway of confusion matrix is that
germayne: It allows you to reconcile 1s and 0, and then basically you're just mapping whether which one you are saying correct correctly, and which one you are saying it wrongly.
germayne: the only question and the gap here is that we haven't talked about how do you actually convert from probability to once and 0, which we will talk about it much later, okay? But you realize that there's a gap here, right? I mentioned above that when you make a prediction for your model.
germayne: Y hat… Y hat always predicts a probability. Y hat will never predict 0 and 1, by the way.
germayne: all of your model, including linear regression so far, you will see that it predicts a probability, right? It's able to tell you in terms of lockouts, and you can actually sort of convert that to probability.
germayne: So, machine learning model usually talks about probability, but why is it that you say probability, but then here it's, like, needs 0 and 1? So, the takeaway for confusion matrix is that it needs it to be
germayne: 1 and 0, which we will talk about it later.
germayne: Okay, so then another very common way to measure performance of classification is actually accuracy. So accuracy, you can basically say, is just the number of total correct prediction divided by the total observation. So if you look at the math, right, it's basically your, your, your, your, your
germayne: It's basically your true positive, those that you get correct Plus your true negative.
germayne: divided by your every… your all observation. Basically… basically, you can see, it's just my…
germayne: True positive plus false positive, plus…
germayne: True negative plus false negative, because
germayne: the sum of all of everything that I make here must be the total number of observations I have, correct?
germayne: right, if I have 100 sample, all the cases I make for true positive, all the cases I get cor- all the cases I get correct, and all the cases I get wrong must be the total cases I have.
germayne: So, what accuracy does is I'm just looking at the total true… the true positive and the true negative that I've made. I take the… I take the ratio.
germayne: Right, so the total number of correct prediction divided by total observation. So you can see here.
germayne: I have my… my… here is my Y.
germayne: Why?
germayne: Basically, my answer key.
germayne: And this is my prediction.
germayne: Why hit?
germayne: Right? So you can see, right, basically what we are doing is that, oh, we're just looking at cases that we predicted correctly, right?
germayne: So, but before we move on, right, anybody…
germayne: wants to see, is there any problem, or why does it say that it's misleading when dealing with imbalanced dataset?
germayne: Anybody knows why.
Zac Ang: Maybe it will over-predict certain things.
germayne: So, if you look at… if you look at this example on the right, right, so like what Zach mentioned, over-predicting certain things, I mean, not exactly over-predicting, but you can see, right, if I'm… if my… if my formula is looking at the total true positive and the true negative.
germayne: If, let's say, I have a lot of, negative cases.
germayne: it might actually over-inflate what I'm performing.
germayne: Right? If you look at the example here, I got 10 transactions.
germayne: And imagine you are working in the fraud team.
germayne: Right? So let's say Noel hired me to work in the fraud team, right? Noel has some kind of system that he's maintaining. He wants me to detect fraud.
germayne: instead of predict… instead of building a machine learning model, I basically build a model for Noel. I just say that everything is normal. I just tell Noelle that everything is okay every day.
germayne: And if you look… if you think from a fraud perspective, fraud is going to be rare, right? Nobody does fraud every time. If you are working in a bank, in terms of financial data, fraud is going to be a very rare occurrence. And you can see intent transactions here.
germayne: 2 of them are fraudulent, 8 of them are normal, but my model that I built for Noel just basically says that it's normal every day. Noel doesn't know it, but my model just basically says it's normal every day.
germayne: So, in this case, you can see that the accuracy is 80%.
germayne: Can see right? Accuracy, 80%. So can we celebrate?
germayne: Oh, yeah, we can celebrate that our model is good.
germayne: Right? So the problem here with accuracy is that
germayne: it doesn't allow you to capture cases, right, if your labour data is not very balanced. You can see it's very imbalanced here, because fraudulent, if you plot the distribution.
germayne: you're going to expect the fraudulent to be very small. Fraud is always going to be very small.
germayne: your transaction is going to be normal most of the time, but fraud is always going to be super, super small. So if you're using accuracy to measure your model performance, you might paint the wrong picture, right?
germayne: So, you guys start to see that, why is evaluation metric very important, because
germayne: If you are not using the right metric, there's going to be two problems here. The first problem is that you yourself do not know whether your model is improving.
germayne: Correct? If, in this example, you're building a fraud model, you're using accuracy, you know fraud is rare.
germayne: You will just basically see that your model is performing at 80% accuracy.
germayne: That may not motivate you to know what is the improvement that you're making. Number two… oh, sorry, number two, the problem here is that if you are presenting these to people, your credibility of the model is going to go down the drain, because you do not know what is the right metric.
germayne: Okay, so you guys can start to see, when we start to introduce metric, every metric got some pros and cons.
germayne: And… Your job is not just to build good models.
germayne: Your job is to also choose a metric that accurately represents the performance, not just for yourself, but for the stakeholders.
germayne: Okay? Because if you're not choosing the right one yourself, then basically you're not going in the right direction.
germayne: You do not know whether you're… you know, after I'm making some changes, whether I'm adding some variables, whether I'm twicking the model, you're not very sure whether your… your… your report, your performance is correct.
germayne: Okay, so that's for accuracy.
germayne: Okay, so now we have another metric called precision, right? So if we think about precision,
germayne: If it's the first time that you are hearing this, you will just imagine precision to just be the total number of cases that you have predicted. So you can look at the… if you look at this formula here.
germayne: true positive plus false positive, basically what it is. If you look at the… if you look at the… the… the confusion matrix, basically it's this…
germayne: So what does it mean? The… the denominator is actually the posi… all the positive cases that you predict.
germayne: all the positive cases you predict. So, what Precision asks is that, out of all the cases that you predict, how many of them are correct?
germayne: I'll repeat again, the denominator here is the total number of predictions that you predict
germayne: 1.
germayne: Out of all the cases that you predicted one, how many of them actually are correct?
germayne: Now, I want to give you guys some intuition here, right?
germayne: Can I actually cheat this metric?
germayne: Can I… can I check this metric? Anybody knows? Is this metric perfect?
germayne: Is there a way I can… I can… I can do something to manipulate this metric?
germayne: So the precision is the number of cases you say, That you predicted one.
germayne: Can I have a high precision? How can I have a high precision?
germayne: Let's say I have no substance, I just want to give a high prediction for precision.
Zac Ang: ridiculous one.
germayne: Exactly, exactly. Because if I predict 1-1, and I get the 1 correct, my position is 100%, right?
germayne: Agree?
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Reason I'm asking you guys this is I want you guys to start to see that there is some trade-off that we can manipulate here.
germayne: And that is an important point later, to answer, how do we actually convert probability to prediction?
germayne: To your actual label. So, just to repeat again, the denominator of the position is basically the cases that you are predicting 1. The top is how many you got correct.
germayne: So, if somebody were to tell me, hey, my position is 100%,
germayne: First thing you want to check is how many cases you predict.
germayne: If the prediction is damn small, very, very small.
germayne: then it's not really very strong, right? I predict very small, and I got a small correct. Not able to capture most of the cases.
germayne: And… The intuition here is that precision can be abused if your model predicts less.
germayne: Right, if I predict last one, then…
germayne: I can get high precision, assuming everything else stays constant, right? So that's precision.
germayne: The counterpart to precision is actually recall.
germayne: Okay? So what is recall?
germayne: Because denominator here, true positive plus false negative. Let me scroll up again and show you where it is.
germayne: So… Precision looks at this quadrant.
germayne: Now, your… your recall basically looks at the squadron.
germayne: All the positive cases.
germayne: Right? So your denominator is all the positive cases. So what is recall? In English terms, recall is basically saying, out of all of the true labels, how many do you get correct?
germayne: So basically, your why, your truer, your true labor equals all of it.
germayne: all of it, for all, so this is a math symbol, for all. For all Y equals to 1, how many do you get correctly? How many do you predict Y hat equals to 1?
germayne: Now, I asked you guys the same question that I asked for precision.
germayne: How do I abuse this?
germayne: Can I, can I abuse this, this metric?
germayne: How do I… For precision, I predict less. What about this metric? How can I abuse?
Lim Hung (Lanson): You put everyone as one.
germayne: Exactly. Now I predict more, right?
germayne: If I predict everything to be 1, I can increase this metric as much as possible. If I predict everything 1, I get maximum lah, right? And the idea here is you notice that these two are like a counterbalance, right?
germayne: Precision is always, like, a trade-off with recall.
germayne: Right? It's a very fine balance.
germayne: If I want to make my model to have high precision, I will… I'm going to… I'm going to… oh, man, I'm going to hurt recall.
germayne: If I'm going to game it to increase recall, I'm going to hurt precision.
germayne: But of course, the best model, I'm not saying that you cannot have high precision, high recall. If your model is, like, fantastic, if you go up to the quadrant.
germayne: If your model is super, super good, let's say you've got a very good model, this tool is, like, very high.
germayne: naturally, your position recall is going to be very high, right? It's a very natural thing.
germayne: But the idea here is that, let's say, right, your model is not very good.
germayne: You don't have a vegetative model.
germayne: The only thing you can manipulate is actually the threshold, right?
germayne: So I'm going to link this back to the whole idea that we mentioned.
germayne: Right? Your model?
germayne: predicts Probability.
germayne: Your model predicts probability, right?
germayne: How can I transform probability to this space?
germayne: Right.
germayne: There's a method for you to transform, and the trade-off will affect your precision and recall.
germayne: Okay? And the idea is actually very simple.
germayne: Right? The idea is, Your model is always going to predict in a probability space.
germayne: what do you guys think that you can do to convert them to 0 and 1? Anybody wants to make a guess?
germayne: So if I have a… my model is predicting everything on the probability space from 0 and 1, right, it's a continuous value. How can I convert them to 0 and 1?
Zac Ang: Realm.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: of your shining.
Chieh Cheng Lai: It's stressful.
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: long.
Teng Lee LIM: Selling it.
germayne: I basically set a threshold, right? I say anything below 0.50, anything above 0.5 is a 1.
germayne: Correct, right? I just basically say, like, okay, anything above 0.5,
germayne: By default, anything above 0.5 becomes 1, anything below 0.5 becomes 0. And you notice that what you can influence, right, is not just improving the model. You can influence this threshold, you can move between left and right.
germayne: The intuition, right?
germayne: Now, I give you guys a… I give you guys a,
germayne: Let me ask you guys something. If I increase the threshold to be very low, what happens?
germayne: So if my threshold to convert to 1 becomes very low.
Josiah Ho: It becomes skipping.
Teng Lee LIM: small one.
germayne: Exactly, then you have more one, correct?
germayne: And if I have more one, what will happen? My recall becomes better, right?
germayne: Now, if you want to increase your threshold to be super strict, hey, everything, only when my model is very confident, then I'll predict one. Only when my model says 0.99999, I predict one, which is, like, very extreme. What will happen? Basically, your position is going to be very good, right?
germayne: You're gonna improve position.
germayne: Because you only predict when you're confident, so whatever that you predicted will be correct, because you are setting a very high bar. So basically, you can see, this threshold matters a lot.
germayne: in… These two metrics.
germayne: Right.
germayne: Okay, the last thing before I move off from position recall.
germayne: There are cases where precision recall matters for different use cases.
germayne: Right.
germayne: Give you guys an example.
germayne: Let's say if you are in medical, you want to detect some kind of illness as a doctor.
germayne: maybe as an individual, some of you might prefer precision, right? Only tell me when you are confident.
germayne: Correct? So, the business case here is that position matters when the cost of making a mistake is very high.
germayne: Now, for recall, again, if you think about the medical standpoint, maybe there are some cases where, oh man, if, if, you know, if you think about, like, back then in COVID, during the COVID cases, maybe if, like, I'm not sure whether the person has issued, the government will basically send you in quarantine, right? Basically, maybe they are trying to optimize on recall.
germayne: I just want to make sure that if I think you have a chance of getting something, I don't want to take the risk, right? If you have any symptoms, I'm going to send you to the quarantine, so maybe I want to optimize when we call.
germayne: So, the question… the question here is.
germayne: As a decision maker, you can build a good model, you can also determine what is the threshold to set the conversion to 1 and 0, and that affects your position and recall. Now, the question to me and to you guys would be that.
germayne: hey, how do I know when to choose that? That is the domain knowledge that you need to decide.
germayne: Right?
germayne: Another example is in the bank.
germayne: Do you guys think recall is a good metric from a bank to catch fraudulent cases?
germayne: let's say Josiah did some stuff, I'm not sure whether he's a fraud. Hey, maybe I'll just banned him.
germayne: Then imagine all your customers is just gonna get banned, so maybe recall is a bad customer experience, correct?
germayne: So maybe for certain bank cases, you might want to optimize on precision. So the takeaway here for you guys to go back with is that from a classification metric standpoint.
germayne: So far.
germayne: Even if you guys don't fully understand the metric, you realize that… you start to realize that each of the metrics has an important decision in the model that you're outputting.
germayne: Right? You can have a model that's very good at precision, you have a very good model at recall, right? Depending on the threshold that you set.
germayne: And the takeaway here that you guys need to understand is, you guys need to ask the right question from the business perspective.
germayne: You guys need to ask… you guys… you guys probably, if you are building the model, you are not the one deciding whether it should be high precision or high recall.
germayne: Try to understand it from a business standpoint.
germayne: Okay? I'm going to skip, specificity, not very common, but it's the opposite, it's basically the true negative rate. I'm going to skip it for the purpose of time, but you guys can just basically see that it's actually very similar to recall, but it's just that looking at the negative perspective.
germayne: Okay, just to wrap up the final score.
germayne: The recall and the precision, they are two separate metrics.
germayne: F1 is actually commonly used by, actually, consider both of them together.
germayne: So basically, instead of looking at precision and recall separately, precision and recall.
germayne: So instead of looking at precision and recall separately, you now have a combined metric, and the rationale for using this combined metric is because
germayne: If F1 score… okay, by the way, right, this, F1 score, even though it's, combining both of them.
germayne: It's actually a balance between precision and recall. So basically, it's weighted equally between precision and recall.
germayne: So what this means is that if overall F1 score increase.
germayne: Right? It must mean that my ideal position of recall is actually increasing. It wouldn't be worse off.
germayne: Okay, because they are weighted equally. Again, it depends, if, let's say, hypothetically, your model is so weird that your recall is suddenly very high, but your position is very low, maybe it might lead to
germayne: an overall increase. This one, I'm not very certain, but we usually use F1 score because we want to measure both precision recall together, right? So it's a… it's a weighted… it's a weighted average. You can see here, mathematically, it's a harmonic mean.
germayne: It… I don't think you guys will get tested in real life, but the idea here is that you cannot take… so there's two types of average, the harmonic average, and basically you have the aromatic average.
germayne: Aromatic average is basically this.
germayne: So basically, this is the mean that you guys are very, very familiar with, right? The math intuition here is that F1 needs to do harmonic is because if you look at the denominator of precision and recall, you realize that they are actually very different, right? This is looking at all the cases that is equals to 1, all the actual cases where label equals to 1,
germayne: this is looking at all the cases where the predictor equals to 1. But you notice that their numerator is actually the same, TP and TP. So harmonic mean, basically, is just a reciprocal average, and that is just the reason, because mathematically, the ratio has a different denominator. So, we do harmonic mean to just
germayne: Average out both position and recall, and we do them in a balanced manner, okay?
germayne: Okay, so I, I will, I will basically stop here.
germayne: First, I think we only have,
germayne: We only have 8 minutes to 9, but the whole idea here is we talk a bit about accuracy.
germayne: We talk a bit about precision, we talk a bit about recall. Specificity is just similar to recall, but for the negative case.
germayne: So I'm not going to go through that. And F1, very common, where we basically just…
germayne: average both position and recall. And you, most of the time, you'll see papers, they will actually present the F1 score.
germayne: Okay? And the F1 score basically balanced between position and recall in a balanced manner.
germayne: For those of you
germayne: that are interested to deep dive more, the F1 score is actually just a generalization of the F-beta score.
germayne: So there's a formula called the F-betta score.
germayne: F… better.
germayne: Oh.
germayne: Yeah, the F-beta. So, essentially, what the F-beta is that maybe you might want a use case where you might want to prioritize recall over precision, or vice versa.
germayne: You can actually have a non-equal weighted
germayne: F-score that basically weighs them differently. But by default, F1 is the common one that people use, and we say that
germayne: We balance both precision and recall, both has important, has, you know, both are important.
germayne: they are equally weighted. So, if I will have an increase in F1 score, I will basically expect
germayne: Either one of it to be better than the other.
germayne: And shouldn't have any degradation, so that's why we look at F1 score as a combined metric.
germayne: Okay, you can see, I'm not trying to rush, but we are nowhere near finishing.
germayne: So maybe, maybe, okay, maybe what I'll do, I'll do, right, is let me wrap up, let me wrap up the classification metric. I think let's do the… let's do the… let's do the regression metric on Saturday, right? Since for the resale house.
germayne: for the resale house Kaggle competition, it's actually on regression metric. Let's do it on Saturday.
germayne: Okay? I don't think we can finish. So what I will do is, let me use the remaining time to talk a bit about the… the… the last metric. So there's also one more metric that's also very common. It's actually called the area under the ROC curve.
germayne: Okay, but I pause here first. Anybody has any questions regarding these that you want me to re-repeat again?
germayne: Or super clear on the takeaway.
germayne: For precision and recall.
germayne: Okay, huh? The one thing you guys should start to realize is that
germayne: if, you know, Jermaine is actually saying that, hey, I need to set a cut, a threshold cut.
germayne: So then, does that mean that when I'm evaluating my position and recall, I'm actually also evaluating them on a specific cut?
germayne: You guys remember, right? So if just now I'm saying that, oh, actually, when, you know, we need to use this… we need to use this, threshold in order to determine this threshold to convert from probability space to
germayne: 1, label 1 and 0. And all the metrics that we talked about above, precision, recall, accuracy, F1, they actually all requires me to
germayne: make this conversion. So then doesn't it mean that
germayne: whatever that I set as a threshold is also getting evaluated, correct?
germayne: And that should be the takeaway, okay? That when you evaluate this metric, it is assuming a specific threshold. So as a… as a creator of the model, the threshold that you set is actually the lever to this metric.
germayne: So, obviously, what you can present is, oh, I can actually set this threshold to get high precision, I can also set this threshold to get high recall.
germayne: But then the question here is that, would there be a way for me to measure a metric without setting a threshold?
germayne: You guys naturally will be thinking of that, right? What if…
germayne: I just want to evaluate my model without setting a threshold.
germayne: Right, so these metrics all require some kind of threshold.
germayne: So the final metric, right, that we just want to talk about is this area under the ROC curve.
germayne: So basically, right, area under the ROC curve is a metric that ranges between 0 to one.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: And obviously, the higher, the better.
germayne: And this metric is basically a metric that allows us to evaluate Across every arbitrary threshold.
germayne: So basically, if a model has higher… AUC ROC score.
germayne: Then, in general, across all thresholds, the model is better, regardless of what threshold. So this model… this metric allows us to evaluate against all thresholds. And what it does is that, if you look at the right-hand side.
germayne: We are actually just plotting
germayne: let me remove this. If you look at the right-hand side here, we're just basically plotting the true positive rate.
germayne: Versus the false positive rate.
germayne: Okay? And… I want… later on, I'll introduce another concept, so it might be a bit confusing, but…
germayne: You will start to see that the true positive rate and the false positive rate, right, is actually similar to the…
germayne: It's similar to what I just asked you guys about this.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: The true positive rate and the false positive rate can again be abused.
germayne: If you set one of the… if you set your threshold to be very strict.
germayne: You're going to have higher true positive rate, correct?
germayne: Because if I increase my threshold to be very high.
germayne: Right? I'm going to draw that curve again, so this is a second… second metric that has this
germayne: This… this thing.
germayne: Okay? But I'm going to walk through with you guys. So again, you can set your threshold between 0 all the way to 1, right? Your model is probability.
germayne: True positive rate, by definition, basically means how many, if you look at true positive rate, it's basically your true positive divided by all the cases that you predicted.
germayne: Wait, give me a second.
germayne: Your true positive rate is your true positive divided by your false positive plus false negative. So if I scroll up here.
germayne: My true positive is here, true positive. I divide it by true positive plus
germayne: false negative, which is here. So basically, out of… so basically, you can… you start to notice this is basically your recaller, right? Right? So if I set it to be… to be…
germayne: force… False positive plus false negative.
germayne: Weird on.
germayne: Yeah, so basically, you can see this is your recall. Basically, this is similar to your recall.
germayne: True positive… Yeah, so basically your true positive divided by true positive plus false negative. So this is your true posit… true positive rate.
germayne: So this is actually similar to your recall.
germayne: Vida.
germayne: So, here, right, if you remember, to get high recall, you just need to predict one more often. So, basically, if I set my threshold to be very low.
germayne: My true positive rate will increase.
germayne: Now, your false positive rate. False positive rate is the cases that you are making false positive.
germayne: to lower force positive, I just need to increase my threshold to be higher, right? If I increase my threshold to be higher, I'm predicting less 1, less cases for me to make false positive. So the idea here is that the AUC-ROC curve, again, right, has this trade-off, right? And…
germayne: what you are basically seeing on this curve here is every specific instance of a specific threshold. So what we are doing here is we are evaluating if I'm able to generate every infinite threshold, I basically can plot the relationship between all my threshold
germayne: Right, so I basically plot a curve. So you can see, I'm basically plotting all of my threshold here. I'll show you guys a diagram later, but the idea here is that
germayne: I'm not just plotting at one single point. I'm plotting across every single point, and therefore I get a curve.
germayne: Now, I'm going to ask you guys a question.
germayne: If my curve is close to… Close to the top.
germayne: Which means that no matter how I adjust my threshold, if I'm adjusting my threshold, I'm actually moving along this curve, right? So then my question to you guys is, is the blue one always better than the green one?
germayne: From a perspective of this curve, I repeat again, huh?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Not always.
germayne: Huh?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Of course, it might be overfitting.
germayne: No, no, no, there's no overfitting. We're not.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, sorry.
germayne: Okay, so I repeat the logical chain again,
germayne: So for ROC AUC curve, we are basically plotting true positive rate versus false positive rate across every threshold. The reason we can get a curve is because
germayne: As I mentioned, each point is a trade-off.
germayne: Right? If I set my threshold very low.
germayne: I'm going to… I'm going to increase false positives
germayne: false positive rate… sorry, true posit… I'm going to increase true positive rate at the expense of my false positive rate. Basically, my false positive rate increased, right? It's a bad thing.
germayne: If I increase my threshold higher.
germayne: I'm actually moving downwards the curve, because
germayne: the number of predictions I'm making is lesser now. My true positive rate suffers, but then my false positive rate actually decreased, which is a good thing.
germayne: Correct? If you look at this curve. So, a curve here basically means I'm checking across all thresholds, right? That's what I'm able to plot.
germayne: Across every threshold. Now, my question to you guys is, for the green one, right, let's say this is Model 1,
germayne: And for the blue one, this is Model 2.
germayne: Is it… can I say the statement that the blue one is actually…
germayne: better than the green one, regardless of what threshold I chose.
germayne: Can I say that?
germayne: I can say that, right? Because no matter what, right, if you look at the curve, no matter what threshold I'm setting.
germayne: Any point on the blue curve is always higher than the green curve.
germayne: Can see, right? Any random point. Any random point that I choose, and the point depends on the model and the threshold.
germayne: So basically, the idea here is that this metric
germayne: Allows us to indirectly measure the performance of our model without thinking about it from a threshold perspective.
germayne: Okay? This metric has a dependency on the threshold. If you set a high threshold, you can get high precision. If you set a low threshold, you get high recall… high recall, low threshold. Then for F1 score, depends on a specific threshold that you set, because you will get a specific precision and recall, right?
germayne: Now, for this specific metric, what we are trying to say is that we are going to again balance this metric.
germayne: And you can see that if the curve, right, is always higher.
germayne: the curve… a higher curve will mean that for any given threshold, the model is inherently better. So what we do is we just look at the area under the curve.
germayne: Okay? If the area of the curve is higher, it means that the curve is now higher, right?
germayne: And if the curve is now higher, it means that no matter what threshold I set, it's definitely going to be better than you, right? And you can see that there's a line here.
germayne: The line in the middle… the line in the middle here will always be a 50% area, so it'll be a 0.5. It'll be a 0.5.
germayne: Right, so that's the line here. So anything that's… so anything that's better than a random guess, better than 0.5, it's just this random line. So if your model is, like, near 0.5, you know that it's not very good, right? So you tend to want to get a higher curve.
germayne: So that's the ideal.
germayne: Okay, I'm just going to show you guys one last illustration before I hand over the code. I will move the regression metrics to Saturday, so we don't need to rush.
germayne: So that I think we have roughly 1 hour to do that, but I'll show you guys this graph.
germayne: for the… Honor…
germayne: Let me see if I can find it.
germayne: Yeah, I'm gonna share my screen.
germayne: Okay, can you guys see my screen?
germayne: Yes, you are.
germayne: Okay, so you can see, basically, right, this is the threshold I'm talking about.
germayne: Hey, sorry, sorry. This is the performance of the model. Let's just create a model performance that's like that.
germayne: This is the threshold that I'm talking about.
germayne: Right.
germayne: This is basically the distribution of
germayne: The… the… the data set that is negative.
germayne: This is a distribution of the data set that is positive. If I set my threshold here, right.
germayne: Right, basically any, anything here, you can see, huh?
germayne: Basically, anything here on the right will be predicted as positive, anything on the left will be predicted as negative. You can see I'm making mistakes on the positive data. You can see, right? This is a distribution on those that has labor equals to 1. But if I put my threshold here, you see this tail, right? This tail, this small area here?
germayne: the label is actually going to be 1, but because of my threshold, everything will become 0. Can you see, right?
germayne: If I set my threshold to be very strict here.
germayne: I'm… I'm making a lot of mistakes on this guy.
germayne: But all my… all my negatives are correct. So you can see here.
germayne: My true posit… my true positive rate actually decreases, but my false positive rate actually is good.
germayne: So you can see, if I move the… if I move the threshold, right, you can see I'm moving along the curve. You can see, right? I'm moving along the curve.
germayne: Is he?
germayne: So, what does it mean? It means that, mathematically, if I measure the area of the curve, I basically can measure against every possible threshold, agreed?
germayne: So, if I have a model that is Super good.
germayne: Imagine yeah, my model that's super good.
germayne: You notice that my threshold, if I put it here, right.
germayne: I'm only making very little mistakes, can you see? The mistakes that I'm making is this, this, this tail, and this tail.
germayne: But if my model is bad.
germayne: Your model is very bad. You can see, no matter what threshold you put, right, it doesn't matter. Can you see?
germayne: I put… I put very high.
germayne: I'm killing away all of this whole rate here.
germayne: I put very low.
germayne: I'm killing away all of the blue behind, can you see?
germayne: So if your model is not good.
germayne: It doesn't really matter what threshold you set.
germayne: And the ROC curve will capture it, because you can see here, it's actually very near 0.5.
germayne: The area here is slightly more than 0.5, so it's actually very bad.
germayne: But if your model is very good, wow.
germayne: Okay? I'll share this.
germayne: Blink to you guys, so that you guys can see.
germayne: Okay, so you can see, the takeaway here is that, unfortunately, this metric, right, not directly optimisable, so this metric cannot be optimized, right? So a lot of those metrics that you see, right, not directly optimisable, but we can use it to measure our model.
germayne: Okay? So… To just, just to sum, just to sum off, Oh… Just to sum off.
germayne: By the end of today, You guys actually have access to these metrics.
germayne: plus this. These are good for beginner, okay? I don't want to introduce any more other metric, right? But maybe if you guys are interested, on Saturday, if you have time, I can talk to you about one more thing about the curve, but for now, I think you guys must be already quite saturated for the classification metric.
germayne: Okay? So this is the takeaway.
germayne: The takeaway, again, right, is
germayne: for any metric in future that you come across, try to understand the trade-off of the metric, right? Try to understand
germayne: what is it that I'm measuring? Because you can… you can see, actually.
germayne: None of them are perfect. Everybody has some issues, okay?
germayne: The one thing to take note, you guys can read the rest on your own, one thing to take note here, right.
germayne: generally, generally, this statement is not completely true. So you can see here.
germayne: is said that this metric is very useful for imbalanced classes. I can tell you guys this is not true, right? I can give a… I can give a counterexample where if I have a lot of label.
germayne: equals to zero.
germayne: Such that if, you know, it is so much more than labor equals to 1,
germayne: I can show that it will completely make the metric useless.
germayne: So it's not generally true that this is effective with imbalanced classes. Usually with imbalanced classes, you need to be very, very careful, because
germayne: Each of your metrics here, Might be skewed by the imbalanced dataset, especially for accuracy.
germayne: Precision, recall, actually, there's a method to read it, but I will leave that after the exercise. I think after the exercise, you guys should be able to get more insight. But for now, I think you guys have, like, the basic fundamental to evaluate a classifier, a classification model, basically, okay?
germayne: Of course, I'm supposed to go through regression metric, but I'll talk about regression metric on Saturday.
germayne: Right?
germayne: and I'll talk about Bayern's variance trade-off on Saturday. Then we'll do the Kaggle. So for today, I will hand off to Soon to do part one for the SKlearn one.
germayne: I think we'll skip regression metric.
germayne: And we see whether we have time to do the end-to-end data science… data set.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, so I'm not going to give a break, but if you need to go by your break, I think just go ahead, okay? So I'll hand off to Soon, so that he can try to finish up.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Yeah, okay.
germayne: Let me stop sharing first.
Soon | NTU: Thank you, Jubin.
Soon | NTU: Okay, let me… Just give me the ball.
Soon | NTU: Can y'all see my screen?
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: Okay, great.
Soon | NTU: Now, we have, okay, we… there are actually three…
Soon | NTU: I would say 4 notebooks in this, 3.3 module.
Soon | NTU: Okay, the quotes. But, because we will cover the last part, which is the Bias, variance, trade-off.
Soon | NTU: On Saturday, right, Jamie?
germayne: Yep, yep.
Soon | NTU: So, we will not go through that today, okay? And also, in the interest of time, we will try to
Soon | NTU: Do it as…
Soon | NTU: I would say at a pace that will make you understand, okay, rather than I rush through, and then in the end.
Soon | NTU: you will find that, you know, I don't understand anything at all. Okay, so that will not, something that we want to, achieve. Okay, so we hope the learning outcome can be very effective. So, I will try to go with, at a normal pace. I try not to rush. Unless you'd like me to
Soon | NTU: Rush, okay, so just let me know, okay? So, the three parts, three Jupyter Notebooks that we have here for Module 3.3, okay, have a… I calculated, I have a total of about 30 over cells.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so… We have to, okay, so, okay, let me…
Soon | NTU: Do we? Okay, so in part one, we will go through this notebook, Jupyter notebook, to show you how to do pre-processing, okay? As, just now we have, learned
Soon | NTU: We need to convert our data Okay, especially our tax data.
Soon | NTU: Right? Which usually we call it categorical variables, right?
Soon | NTU: into numbers.
Soon | NTU: Right? Because machine learning algorithms can only work with mathematics, can only work with numbers, okay? So that is usually one of the steps that we need to do is to pre-process our data, meaning convert the text
Soon | NTU: data to numbers, okay? For the numbers.
Soon | NTU: That come with the data set, that one, we will talk about it later in the second half after we talk about that encoding game.
Soon | NTU: Now, pre-processing categorical variable means we are going to convert this text, right, into number. Okay, so there are two commonly used techniques, okay? One is called label encoding, the other one is called one-ho encoding.
Soon | NTU: Right? So, Jamin has already explained to you what is the meaning of Label encoding, right?
Soon | NTU: Any… anyone is still not,
Soon | NTU: Clear of what this label encoding is trying to achieve.
Soon | NTU: Anyone?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so if you're not sure, just try to…
Soon | NTU: just, raise a question so that I can clarify, okay? And I hope…
Soon | NTU: along the way, when I try to explain the meaning of each of these quotes, okay, it can help you to understand better what is the meaning of the coding, right? Now, in this
Soon | NTU: code block, right, we… usually we will need to import some basic library, okay, to do
Soon | NTU: Encoding, okay, meaning to convert all these texts.
Soon | NTU: two numbers. Now, firstly, we will use the standard
Soon | NTU: methods, okay, the standard function that come with pandas.
Soon | NTU: And then later, we will show you to…
Soon | NTU: how to do encoding again in SKlearn, the scikit-learn library, okay? And I will explain to you why do we need to do
Soon | NTU: Show you two methods.
Soon | NTU: Okay. No.
Soon | NTU: Okay, you see, in this… data frame. Okay, so this is a color column that we have,
Soon | NTU: Just make it simple, because our intention is to show you how to convert the text, the categorical value into numbers. Okay, so this…
Soon | NTU: Is December cool?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so if you run it, you will get an output like this.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so…
Soon | NTU: Now, rate is converted to a number, okay? So there will be an extra column called color encoded, so I believe
Soon | NTU: You should know how to read the…
Soon | NTU: Panda syntax, right? Okay, so this means we are going to create a new column in this data frame.
Soon | NTU: The value of this will be… Quantit-only numbers.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this number actually comes from the CAP code.
Soon | NTU: Right, categorical code. So, what basically this is doing is we'll convert all this color into a number.
Soon | NTU: By default, these categorical value are arranged according to the alphabetical order. So when you convert into numbers, right.
Soon | NTU: Duh.
Soon | NTU: Alphabetical order means… The blue will come first.
Soon | NTU: Followed by the green, because…
Soon | NTU: G come out the blue, right? Come out the B, and then followed by the rate. So, blue will have a value of 0,
Soon | NTU: Green, value 1, and red, value of 2.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is how you are…
Soon | NTU: The new column will look like after you have
Soon | NTU: Converted after you have encoded the color.
Soon | NTU: Okay? Now, as you go to the training step, right.
Soon | NTU: You need to drop this column. Drop means to remove.
Soon | NTU: Okay, but just to show you.
Soon | NTU: Just to compare before and after the conversion, so that you understand, oh, this tool is actually for rape.
Soon | NTU: 1 is actually from green, blue is zero, and so on. Of course, if you have some number in mind, right, to help me to remember, oh, I used a call rate, let's say, 50,
Soon | NTU: then you also can, put in your own, custom order. Okay, but I think this…
Soon | NTU: Encoding technique is basically to show you that the main intention is to convert your text value to numbers.
Soon | NTU: Okay?
Soon | NTU: Any question?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yeah, I have a question. For the color red, green, blue, green, red.
Chieh Cheng Lai: So, so, if we have a lot of the column, more than, here is 5… phi roll.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Do we need to input all the roles in order for covering CARA encoded?
Soon | NTU: Okay, the conversion, the encoding is… by column.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so if you have an encoding
Soon | NTU: 2 for red, 1 for green. If you have another column, call color again, okay, so that encoding will not be used for the second column.
Soon | NTU: You have to define your own mapping.
Soon | NTU: For each of the, encodings.
Chieh Cheng Lai: No, no, no, no, I mean that if, because right now the color, we have, here.
Chieh Cheng Lai: one column.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Only have, 5th row. Only have 5 rows.
Soon | NTU: which is…
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yeah, so if we have… I mean, for example, we have data, definitely more than 5 rows, we have 100, I mean, one,
Chieh Cheng Lai: 10,000 row. So… So, in this case.
Chieh Cheng Lai: So, the DF equal to PD data frame, do we need to, I mean, how to interpret so many rows on here, on the DF?
Soon | NTU: Okay, this is, our very oversimplified data frame with only one column.
Soon | NTU: Okay, and yes, hello.
Soon | NTU: 5 rows. Now, if you, let's say, randomly add more rows, right? Let's say, for example, I'm going to add
Soon | NTU: A few more.
Soon | NTU: Right? So make it 8 rows, right? 9 rows. So, if you run it.
Soon | NTU: You're gonna have the same kind of encoding scheme.
Soon | NTU: In which rate will definitely be 2.
Soon | NTU: green is 1, and blue is 0. Okay, so your column after encoding will be like this.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: No matter how many columns… not many rows you have, as long as you have a green here, this new encoded row would definitely be a 1.
Soon | NTU: Okay, likewise for red, and likewise for blue.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Oh, okay, okay, I understand. So, I just input the…
Chieh Cheng Lai: the column name that I want to be converted.
Soon | NTU: Right, yes. Okay.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Regardless of the.
Soon | NTU: Yeah, the column name is important, because if not, then the pandas will not know
Soon | NTU: How we should convert, because
Soon | NTU: whether is it 0, 1, 2, okay, the N number all depends on how many unique value there are in a color. In Nixis, we only have 3, right?
Soon | NTU: What if there are 10? So, there could be up to 9 here if we have 10 colors in the original data set.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: Because Pandas and Python is zero-based, it can always count something from zero, so that is why the first element is zero.
Shilpa Kangya: Can we assign the encoded value?
Shilpa Kangya: Can we assign the encoded value by ourselves? This is the generated one, right?
Soon | NTU: Sorry, I, I can't really hear your, your question.
Shilpa Kangya: What I'm trying to ask is,
Shilpa Kangya: Right now, 0, 1, and 2 are generated, right?
Soon | NTU: Yes.
Shilpa Kangya: So, can we hardcode these values?
Shilpa Kangya: As per, my.
Soon | NTU: You can also have your own, numeric?
Soon | NTU: So-called, numbering scheme.
Soon | NTU: Tom, your…
Soon | NTU: color, let's say red, you choose to start with 1, because it's a favorite color, and then followed by green, 2, blue, it's 3, and so on. Don't…
Soon | NTU: No need to count from, zero.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Shilpa Kangya: Okay.
Soon | NTU: Yeah, but the thing is, when we encode, right, it's basically to convert the value
Soon | NTU: Categorical value, which is text, into number.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we don't really, like, concern about, you know, what is the number, because when machine learning trains, whether you give it a 1 for the rate or 0 for the rate, it's not going to be of any… any, importance, huh?
Shilpa Kangya: Okay.
Soon | NTU: Okay, the important thing is, each must be a number that you feed into the machine learning to train it, right, and not tax.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Teng Lee LIM: Hi.
Teng Lee LIM: That's how you mentioned that we can… we will drop the color column, right, when we do… when we input the data for machine learning.
Teng Lee LIM: Am I right?
Soon | NTU: Yes, yes.
Teng Lee LIM: After that, because based on the color-encoded column, right, you won't be able to…
Teng Lee LIM: How do we know that? What does number 1 stand for after we profit?
Soon | NTU: Yeah, yeah, that's a very good question. Okay, so that is why, in the next, section of the notebook, right, we are going to use,
Soon | NTU: sklearn library to do the same thing, right? Instead of using the pandas way of encoding, we use the sklearn way of encoding. Because after you encode it using the sklearn.
Soon | NTU: Your original, categorical value.
Soon | NTU: will still be… Save somewhere for your future reference.
Teng Lee LIM: Okay, Ken, thank you.
Soon | NTU: Yes.
Soon | NTU: Because… because, like, this Python will… Pandas will automatically drop it, because it is assumed that you will not need the text, original text data for your machine learning training, okay? So that is why we have all these, encoding
Soon | NTU: As one of the very important pre-processing steps to convert your text to numbers, Right?
Soon | NTU: So… Let me continue. Okay, is it… Is it…
Teng Lee LIM: Thank you.
Soon | NTU: You're welcome. Now, the next step is to, okay, let's see how much we can cover, okay? If not, Germaine, I think we can overflow
Soon | NTU: put it into the next session, right, Jamie?
germayne: Okay, okay. But next session, just to let you guys know, also a lot of items. So…
germayne: Yeah.
Soon | NTU: Just, just, okay, okay, I'll, I will try, I will try, again, to, to clear as much.
germayne: Maybe, maybe for, for… we see whether if we can overflow today first, maybe a bit.
germayne: If you guys are okay, a bit lah. We see how much we can do lah. We just see how much we can do. No worries, no worries. Okay, yeah, yeah, we play by ear.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, sorry, sorry, continue on you.
Soon | NTU: Because I think it's also, good to maybe take some of the questions, otherwise, later it will be asked, then it'll be a bit out of the contact. I have to remember, you know, what actually is,
Soon | NTU: your actual, so-called the intention. Now, the second, technique that we usually use, right, I would say more commonly used, is the one-hot encoding.
Soon | NTU: This is similar to the encoding scheme, the labor encoding that you've seen just now. But instead of converting each of these texts into a value.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we are using this
Soon | NTU: binary value, which is a number of either 1 or 0, okay, to represent the original text value.
Soon | NTU: Okay, if the text… okay, let's, let's continue.
Soon | NTU: With this, example. Now, the command is pandas get dummies. Okay, so you're telling the pandas, oh, my encoder, encoding the column to be encoded. What?
Soon | NTU: to be hot… one hot encoded is the color column. Anyway, we only have one color, okay? And after encoding with the get dummies.
Soon | NTU: You'll have a… new data frame, okay.
Soon | NTU: Like this.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so as you can see, your original column is gone.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so that's how technically asks, hey, what happened to my original, color column? Okay, so does it mean that I have to save the value somewhere, so that in the future I can know, oh.
Soon | NTU: 2 is actually for grade, right? Now, if you can see this additional column that I added, right?
Soon | NTU: The naming convention is usually The original column name, Underscore the…
Soon | NTU: the original categorical value which are found in the color column, okay? So since we have 3 value, right? So the new columns that are added to the data frame
Soon | NTU: Will people have a column name of color blue.
Soon | NTU: Color green, and color red.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is the…
Soon | NTU: How the end result will look like after you have performed a one-haul encoding on your color column.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so now, if you have 10 values, 10 unique values.
Soon | NTU: purple, white, black, and so on, okay? So, likewise, you have 10 additional new columns added.
Soon | NTU: we've, name.
Soon | NTU: Color underscore white, color underscore black, and so on.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so the more value you have in the color, of course, the more column that this, get dummy will give you, right? So there will always come a point
Soon | NTU: you shouldn't apply to this one-haul encoding to just now Jeremy mentioned, okay?
Soon | NTU: Column, which is high cardinality.
Soon | NTU: means you have 1 million rows, you have almost 900,000 value. So if you apply a one-hour encoding on this column, you're going to have a very, very high dimension, okay? So that is usually not advisable.
Soon | NTU: Yes, this is, usually the naming convention, okay, so…
Soon | NTU: You have to tell, get that dummies what column you want to…
Soon | NTU: one out, end quote. Because after this, right, not only will you get the additional new column.
Soon | NTU: Based on the value, Of the original color, but this color column will be dropped.
Soon | NTU: color column will be dropped. Okay, so, as you can see here.
Soon | NTU: Since this color encoded come from the first step, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so that it's why it's still retained.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so at least now you can see rain, Is it?
Soon | NTU: Rid?
Soon | NTU: Is it blue? If it's not blue, then this will be a false, okay? Likewise for green, this is…
Soon | NTU: not a green, because 2 is red, right? Then this will be a false. If this is red, yes, so this will be a true. Okay, so it's quite difficult for you to…
Soon | NTU: look at this true and false, right? But I…
Soon | NTU: B.
Soon | NTU: thing I can do, data type.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is another…
Soon | NTU: So, after converting all the true and false into 1 and 0, okay, so in pandas, in Python, 0 is a force, 1 is a true. Okay, so…
Soon | NTU: to Israel.
Soon | NTU: So, this is for blue, so this is zero, this is green.
Soon | NTU: This is 0, and the column rate is 1, okay? So, in order to interpret
Soon | NTU: Whether that road has, rigged, color, originally.
Soon | NTU: you have to see which column is giving you a 1, right? Because out of these three values, only one of the columns can be 1, the rest are all 0. So that's why it is called 1 hot encoding. So this is a hot column.
Soon | NTU: This is hot, because originally it's green, Right.
Soon | NTU: Right. After one encoding, it is green in the second column.
Soon | NTU: So you have a 1 in the second column, and so on and so forth.
Soon | NTU: Right? So… Clear with the, one hot encoding.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so let's… go to perform the encoding with the Psychic Learn. Okay, so… We will have…
Soon | NTU: Likewise, a data frame with only 5
Soon | NTU: value in the color column. We do not want to make the whole thing too complicated. Now.
Soon | NTU: to do one labor encoding using the psychic-learn, okay, so we have to make use of this
Soon | NTU: Method, dysfunction, or label and code.
Soon | NTU: Right? And then we create a label encoder object.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this label-encoded object is the one that will store wherever
Soon | NTU: The original value of the color column.
Soon | NTU: Okay, because after transformation, you'll need to drop the column somewhere, right? Some… in your code, okay. But this label encoder is the object that will still contain all the original information in your comma column. Okay, so let's run this.
Soon | NTU: Right? The value are still the same as before.
Soon | NTU: Because the value here will be sorted alphabetically by default.
Soon | NTU: And then you will have… 0 for blue, one for green, and red for… Number 2.
Soon | NTU: Right? So there's no difference between doing this
Soon | NTU: Using scikit-learn and doing this using Pandas, okay?
Soon | NTU: Now, where is the original
Soon | NTU: value stored, let's say, before we feed the ML model, right, for training, okay? So you can take a look at this,
Soon | NTU: Yeah, it's, variable call, category.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so if you're going to print this out, right?
Soon | NTU: Kill any…
Soon | NTU: Okay, reprocessing, let me run…
Soon | NTU: The categories, or category.
Soon | NTU: Copy.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so… So…
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is, one just to show you that you are able to stop, look at the original value, okay, of your blue, green, and red inside the
Soon | NTU: color column of your data frame, okay? So because of that, you…
Soon | NTU: should try to make use of the psychic learn to do the encoding, okay, as much as possible, rather than the, the pandas way of encoding, right? Unless you're doing a very quick
Soon | NTU: You know, prototype, and just wanted to try to test out some of the,
Soon | NTU: ideas, right? So, I think using the basic pandas.
Soon | NTU: can be one other option for you to explore, but for your actual so-called usage, right, Sakit-learn Library Arc is always the preferred way of doing the encoding.
Soon | NTU: Okay? So… Any question up to this point?
Gwen Lim: I have a question regarding categories and labeling. Is there a way, or do you suggest any efficiencies when it comes to indexing all of these labels?
Soon | NTU: Is… is there a way to what?
Gwen Lim: the best, best practices for indexing all of the labeling. Say, for example, if I finish the labeling in one system, and then I wanted to kind of use the same kind of labeling
Gwen Lim: happens in another data set? Is there, like, an efficient way to do it, or, you know, something that's kind of, like, best, best, best, best example of.
Soon | NTU: The indexes for this 0, 1, 2, You, you mean?
Gwen Lim: Yes, because some of the… because some of the label mappings that we can do across different datasets are… can be considered similar, right, in function, because the identity of these categories are the same.
Gwen Lim: Is there a way for us to be able to carry these labeling structures over into a new system entirely?
Soon | NTU: Well, this labeling structure, are you referring to the blue, green, red, and so on?
Gwen Lim: Yes, yes, yes, and any other values or variables that are in the.
Soon | NTU: Because your color column, right, sometimes this kind of value can be very, specific to your own use case, okay? You may choose to call this blue
Soon | NTU: bookcase B.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so I would say the main intention here is, regardless of the value in your dataset, okay, if this is text content.
Soon | NTU: You need to convert into a number.
Soon | NTU: Okay, and this number, numbering scheme.
Soon | NTU: There is no best practice to detect whether it should start from 1, 2, 3, or with a step of 10, 10, 20, 30, or, you know, there is no such a requirement or best practice for this
Soon | NTU: Okay, so it's basically… Yeah, so it's solely to convert your text into a number, and first off.
Soon | NTU: Okay, because whether this is 10, 20, 30, it's not going to make any difference to the, improving the performance of your model.
Gwen Lim: Okay, noted. Thank you very much.
Soon | NTU: Yeah, yeah, they're welcome.
Soon | NTU: Bone… Okay, so… Okay, let me continue with…
Soon | NTU: Okay, so I have already shown you that the original mapping
Soon | NTU: So-called the categorical value of the color.
Soon | NTU: can still be traced back, right, using the,
Soon | NTU: label encoding object in scikit-learn, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so, likewise, if we apply the one-hole encoder.
Soon | NTU: We will get back the same result as appenders.
Soon | NTU: encode… one hot encoding, function. Now.
Soon | NTU: So this is some… a very good example. So, after you have encoded the value.
Soon | NTU: The original color column is removed.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so, so… Scikit-learn will not require you to do this removal of the column manually.
Soon | NTU: Right? You would just do it.
Soon | NTU: one command, you will take care of both actions, right? And code, and remove the original column.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we have already talked about converting the…
Soon | NTU: categorical or text value to numbers to prepare our data for training, machine learning training, okay? How about numbers?
Soon | NTU: Okay, phone numbers, we… There will still be numbers.
Soon | NTU: But we have to go through this pre-processing step.
Soon | NTU: We call it, scaling, okay? So, scaling, it means we will adjust the range of the data so that different columns
Soon | NTU: will contribute equally to the final prediction. Okay, because if you have a large number in one of the features.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so during the machine learning training, you likely will have this feature
Soon | NTU: That has the large number, okay, to dominate the whole
Soon | NTU: prediction. It becomes likely that this
Soon | NTU: To feature that have large number.
Soon | NTU: will have.
Soon | NTU: Larger contribution to the prediction, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, now let's see what it means by that. So, for scaling, we have
Soon | NTU: This is what we call the standardization.
Soon | NTU: And the function that we use is the standard scaler. Okay, so making use of this.
Soon | NTU: We create a scalar object, This scalar object, Whoa.
Soon | NTU: Called a feed transform.
Soon | NTU: On your data frame.
Soon | NTU: And then… You have to… Tail… this… scalar… Right.
Soon | NTU: What are the columns to be scaled?
Soon | NTU: Again.
Soon | NTU: Since we only have one column, so I think that is,
Soon | NTU: We have two columns, okay? All are numerin.
Soon | NTU: So, you have… An output like this.
Soon | NTU: Okay, let me… Okay, so you have an output like this. Okay, so what does it mean?
Soon | NTU: To you?
Soon | NTU: What does it mean you have a feature like this? So, from the original value, 123456, you end up having the same number in both feature 1 and 2, okay? So this is an effect of scaling.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so I can see… Okay, so… Question.
Soon | NTU: Yeah. So… After scaling, We have the same number in Feature 1 and 2.
Soon | NTU: Right? Okay, so from here, you can't really tell what's the impact of
Soon | NTU: what's the purpose of scaling? Because it works. They are… they are the same, right? Okay, so now, how about making this…
Soon | NTU: You see 40,000.
Soon | NTU: We change this to a different scale, a very, very large number, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay? Comparing with this and this, King.
Soon | NTU: Let's see.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we have a feature 2 in the different scale now, bigger than your feature 1 number. Okay, so…
Soon | NTU: Applying under our… Scaling using the standard scaler.
Soon | NTU: Let's see what we can come up with.
Soon | NTU: Is this C the same?
Soon | NTU: It's still the same, right?
Soon | NTU: Minus 1.22.
Soon | NTU: thing I have, okay.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so it's very close, okay? So during training.
Soon | NTU: when you use this feature to predict the value of your Y, right, okay, so there will not be any, let's say, special, let's say, feature 1 or feature 2 is dominating the whole prediction.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: It's something like your linear regression, you have a very huge coefficient, right? So when you predict likely that your Y will
Soon | NTU: Have a value of
Soon | NTU: close to that coefficient, the large coefficient, right? So the effect of the scaling will make everything come to the same scale.
Soon | NTU: In this case, it's, in a, in a… brain shock, minus…
Soon | NTU: It's about negative 1 in 1. Okay, so all these values are in the… having a mean of
Soon | NTU: 0, and a standard deviation of 1.
Soon | NTU: Bing.
Soon | NTU: Any question?
Soon | NTU: At this point in time, I, I will, I will try to go…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I do understand, if after the sanitation, everything's the same, then why…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Why, why have this in,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: In the science… in the science… science key.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Fiber thing, you know.
Soon | NTU: Why do we do this?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, like, I understand mini-max, you know, I mean, the main thing about…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Normalization is to get some sort of a… you try to make sure that you have your scale right. But yeah, after normalization is all the same, then why do… why do we want to bother about this?
Soon | NTU: Okay, when numbers are in a different scale, right, so usually we would, okay, let's, let's say, give you an example, okay? We don't talk about machine learning
Soon | NTU: Okay, all the AI, okay? So, let's say…
Soon | NTU: I have, after taking a grant.
Soon | NTU: Okay? So my bill come out to be… 10… let's see… $19.80.
Soon | NTU: $19.89, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so do you mind rounding up to… 20 dollars.
Soon | NTU: is okay, right? Because the 20 cent is so small compared to the $30, right? So usually, yeah, keep the change up, right? So, you can see $20 versus $0.20.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: If the fare, let's say we go back to 50 years ago, right? You take a taxi, and your fare is $20, 20 cents, okay? Will you say, keep the change?
Soon | NTU: I pay you $1, keep the chain.
Soon | NTU: No, right?
Soon | NTU: Because the quantum is so different now, okay, $20 versus $0.20, okay, that is…
Soon | NTU: how many times difference, okay? Because the 26 is so small, so for me, right, maybe for the others, you do not mind rounding it up, okay? But if the fare is only, $5,
Soon | NTU: You can give a $50 and say, keep the change a lot.
Soon | NTU: No, right. Okay, so you have to see, if you have a big number, right, usually the big number would dominate your decision when you make, right? Whether to keep the change or not. $5, you know, I only have $50. So, of course, I will tell the grab driver to give me the change back lah, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so like when it's machine learning, you will have to be careful, okay, if your number are not in the same scale.
Soon | NTU: Okay, you have to do something so that everything is scaled to the same Numbers.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so then, during prediction, then you'll be fair for all the features, okay? And you will not say, oh, because I predicted the… because you did not scale your value, right, your column, then you tend to say, oh, the… because…
Soon | NTU: In your housing prediction data set, right, which is the column that is having the most The highest value.
Soon | NTU: That will be done.
Soon | NTU: Column that will determine whether you will
Soon | NTU: Have a high property price or not.
Soon | NTU: That column, because the value is very high.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so I think when we do the Kaggle, probably we can try, with the scaling and with scaling, you can see what is the result.
Soon | NTU: Okay, anywhere.
Soon | NTU: Yeah, thank you. Thank you for the question. Okay, so for mean-max scaling.
Soon | NTU: Likewise, we're going to apply this formula to rescale the column, each of all the columns, to a fixed range of, usually from 0 to 1, using this formula.
Soon | NTU: Me.
Soon | NTU: So, we're gonna apply this formula to our… Data set here.
Soon | NTU: Okay, let me try not to… I mean?
Soon | NTU: Otherwise, you will have a different result from mine, right? So, after mean max, you'll see your number is also become very small. Small means it is, I think, around the range of, you know, 0 to 1.
Soon | NTU: Right? If you use a mean-max scalar, It'll be 0 to 1.
Soon | NTU: If you use, standard scalar, okay, the number can be negative.
Soon | NTU: Right, because, you know, normal distribution is, centered around the mean. If the mean is zero.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so your X can be negative as well, symmetrical.
Soon | NTU: Right?
Soon | NTU: So far, standard scalar MEMAX, any, any question before…
Soon | NTU: Okay, so…
Chieh Cheng Lai: Sorry, I have one question. So, in this case, the means max scaling for the standard
Chieh Cheng Lai: The, scaling will be preferable to be used.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Just so I'm sure.
Soon | NTU: Can you purchase a standard scaler?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yes.
Soon | NTU: Usually we will use the… this… Standard scaler, Okay.
Soon | NTU: Because this… Dennis Giller. Because this one is very sensitive to, outliers.
Chieh Cheng Lai: And boosted.
Soon | NTU: What if your max is, you know.
Soon | NTU: 10 billion, okay? So if you use this formula to do a scaling up, you're gonna end up with, you know, astronomical numbers somewhere.
Soon | NTU: It may be very, your, your, your, your scaling would be very… Distorted, right?
Soon | NTU: Because there's a huge number involved in your formula.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Okay.
Chieh Cheng Lai: G.
Soon | NTU: Right?
Soon | NTU: If there's no question, I will not go through the normalization, because normalization is more meaningful when we talk about the
Soon | NTU: NLP, natural language processing, okay? So, basically, what it means is, instead of doing normalization, instead of doing the scaling at a column level, you're doing row-wise.
Soon | NTU: Okay, and for the actual usage of it, right, we will just…
Soon | NTU: maybe cover this either on Saturday, or maybe during the NLP session.
Soon | NTU: Right, in 3.9.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, too, so, so, so far, right? Can I conclude that?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, so far what we have learned,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: the scaling methods are not very, not very good, lah. I mean, quite can skew either here or there, you know.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: There are pros and cons to each of them, but each of them tend to…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: the content is very bad lah, that, that I… I think if I give her a choice, I probably won't use them.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So far, based on the things we've learned.
Soon | NTU: It is a choice, especially when you have a numeric column, numeric feature with a.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, I'm talking about numeric, because it's like, it's like, either the number… the outlier is very big, then you, you skew one, one, one reason, or the standard one, you know, if it's like, you know, you, you measure them all the same, so…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: It seems like so far, the method, yeah, it's good to know them, but in terms of usage, probably not very, not that…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Not a lot, lah, I mean, the way I understand it, I'm not sure. Based on the conclusion that I see so far, lah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Not sure whether it might be on the right track or not, but yeah. Seems that we…
germayne: Noel, no, I don't think that should be the takeaway.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
Soon | NTU: We have a different way of, treating the, outliers, okay? Okay. Okay, okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Nobody doesn'.
Soon | NTU: Your outlier definitely will be there in your dataset, okay?
Soon | NTU: But you have to see, on a case-by-case basis, how you're going to treat these outliers.
Soon | NTU: Sometime you have to discard them for your data analysis.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Right.
Soon | NTU: glue them.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
Soon | NTU: Because we do not… are not living in a perfect world.
Soon | NTU: validator. It comes with a lot of noise.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay. Anyway, I was… I was thinking that, you know, like, you know, there'll be, like, you know, I mean, maybe, I mean, for me, at least, I learned a few things, and I will… I will pick and… pick the one that can seem to cover more… more… more cases than… or more scenarios than another.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So that's where I'm coming from. Maybe I'd be wrong in this case for machine learning, yeah, so, okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, so I'm, like, looking forward to a better method lah, you know, so we can stick to it, you know, and use it as often as possible.
Soon | NTU: You will know even more, maybe, after the Kaggle.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay. Okay, okay.
Soon | NTU: Now, let's… let's continue. We only have around…
Soon | NTU: 15 minutes, right? So, if you can exit the time by 10 minutes. Okay, so max, huh? Okay. Now, how about handling missing value? So, we have talked so much on converting the categorical text value to number, as well as transforming all your number
Soon | NTU: To the comparable scale.
Soon | NTU: How are we gonna do?
Soon | NTU: handle missing value. So, missing value are something like this, right? So, in…
Soon | NTU: We have a very simple data frame, a data set with two columns, okay? Now, each of these columns have a missing value.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: So, you can take a look at this data frame.
Soon | NTU: Feature 1 has a missing value in there.
Soon | NTU: Third row, and then feature 2 as a missing value in the second row.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is something we would like to also prepossess, right? Because if you have a hole like this, right.
Soon | NTU: machine learning model will have problems, so… because mathematically, if you want to add two numbers, that two numbers must be numbers, right? You don't add something with some unknown
Soon | NTU: then you will not know how… equal to what, okay, so that will be unknown as well. Okay, so we do not want to end up with missing value in our data frame, so that's why we need to go through this
Soon | NTU: Basically, there are two strategies, okay?
Soon | NTU: Either you remove them, you drop them, Okay.
Soon | NTU: When you drop, right, it can be column-wise or row-wise.
Soon | NTU: in Penders.
Soon | NTU: on you.
Soon | NTU: And the second strategy, the second method is to impute. Impute means to fill in the blank
Soon | NTU: Right? With some value.
Soon | NTU: So that value can be a mean.
Soon | NTU: medium and mode, yeah, depending on the data type. So we usually, for…
Soon | NTU: Number, we don't… we use a meme.
Soon | NTU: Okay? Unless there is some kind of, outliers.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we are trying to use the median. So, mean…
Soon | NTU: It's one of the commonly used strategies for Filling the blank, so this…
Soon | NTU: After you apply the simple impute, right, again, this feed transform, as…
Soon | NTU: you can actually split the two, feed and then transform, but I think Pandas provides you a…
Soon | NTU: Circulent provides you a very convenient function for you to do in
Soon | NTU: fit and transform at one go, okay? So, what are we going to do?
Soon | NTU: Which column are 2B?
Soon | NTU: imputed.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: So… Any missing… any column with missing value.
Soon | NTU: Right? Because we have already identified the DM missing, these two columns.
Soon | NTU: Queen.
Soon | NTU: And then your DF imputed.
Soon | NTU: will have… All the value, missing value, Fill up with the mean, Of the visual one.
Soon | NTU: Okay, if you have missing value here, what's the mean of this 1 and 2?
Soon | NTU: 1.5, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so after imputation, you have a 1.5 here. Likewise, for feature 2, what's the mean of 4 and 6?
Soon | NTU: Frankly.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so after imputation, you'll find that your data frame is now having
Soon | NTU: Both columns, without any missing value.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so that is one of the very important steps. Now.
Soon | NTU: But of course, if during your EDA, right, you discover that most of the columns have value.
Soon | NTU: There are no missing value, then you probably will not have to go through this imputation step.
Soon | NTU: The data is very clean.
Soon | NTU: No missing value. Then you can proceed to the next step to do your… whatever.
Soon | NTU: Right?
Soon | NTU: Any question?
Soon | NTU: on the… Handling missing value.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so let's see… we have, okay, 2 more cells.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so 2 more cells in, 10 minutes.
Soon | NTU: Let me rerun this.
Soon | NTU: So, we have already done all the pre-processing, so assuming EDA done as well. Okay, so what is the next step we need to do?
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: Is to go through this process of training the model.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so for simplicity, we will not use whatever data frame we did, but instead.
Soon | NTU: We will use, some synthetic data.
Soon | NTU: Okay, making use of this, make classification function to generate 1,000 data point.
Soon | NTU: Okay, and each data point has… 20 column.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is a logistic regression classification model, so there are only two classes.
Soon | NTU: Okay?
Soon | NTU: And then we… pray the logistic regression, and then feed, okay? So the training is only just one liner.
Soon | NTU: fee.
Soon | NTU: Weave. Your.
Soon | NTU: Extreme, so this is the data.
Soon | NTU: without the… that target variable, without the labor column. Your labor column is here.
Soon | NTU: So this is the column.
Soon | NTU: Containing your model answer, which the model is trying to predict.
Soon | NTU: So… Let me… Continuing.
Soon | NTU: Rundles.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we have trained a logistic regression model, Okay, and this model now is able to…
Soon | NTU: Make prediction games, so… Since we have already split the data in two.
Soon | NTU: 80% for training, right?
Soon | NTU: 20% for testing.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this training phase, of course, we only use the training data.
Soon | NTU: Because as long as we have not completed the training.
Soon | NTU: We should not use the test data.
Soon | NTU: for any… Or anything, right? Because otherwise, there will be this thing called, data leakage.
Soon | NTU: Yep.
Soon | NTU: No.
Soon | NTU: Your test data is in… X test.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so using the model, we predict.
Soon | NTU: the Y test, okay, the Y prediction in here.
Soon | NTU: And then, you will have…
Soon | NTU: another… call another function called the predict probability, okay? So the difference between this and this is, this one will give you
Soon | NTU: Dope.
Soon | NTU: Line 4 will give you the prediction of 1 or 0, whereas this Y probability will give you the corresponding probability of each of these 0 and 1. Okay, let me run this.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so let me give you an idea of what this prediction will look like.
Soon | NTU: green.
Soon | NTU: So… this is how the prediction would look like. So, since we have, Okay, so this is,
Soon | NTU: the prediction.
Soon | NTU: Right? So the first… The first, sample in your X, your test data, is 0.
Soon | NTU: Second is zero.
Soon | NTU: third one is 1, and so on, okay? And this is because Our probability is… like this.
Soon | NTU: Okay, this is something internally stored in the…
Soon | NTU: succulent library, okay? But you can tell from here, just now, Jamie mentioned it is… because this logistical question, right? So what is actually the threshold
Soon | NTU: That determines whether it is a 0 or 1.
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Bye.
Soon | NTU: 0.5, yes, very good, Philip. Okay, so now, if you look at the…
Soon | NTU: Probability of the first value, okay?
Soon | NTU: dew point.
Soon | NTU: This is exponential.
Soon | NTU: 2, right? Minus 2, so it's 0.03.
Soon | NTU: Is it more than 0.5?
Soon | NTU: No, right? So…
Soon | NTU: That's why your predicted value is zero, okay? How about 2… 6 to the power of 10 minus… 2?
Soon | NTU: 0.06 is still less than 0.5. So, second prediction is still 0.
Soon | NTU: Now, how about the third one?
Soon | NTU: Third one is… 9 to the power.
Soon | NTU: E minus…
Soon | NTU: 1, so is 0.9, right? 0.9 is more than 0.5. That is why the third prediction is 1.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is done internally, right?
Soon | NTU: But because we wouldn't work with these numbers, but we will…
Soon | NTU: It's more, easily readable based on 0 and 1, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay? So I think… Okay, so let's continue with this.
Soon | NTU: So now, after we have obtained the prediction in Ypredict, so how do we know all these predictions are
Soon | NTU: You know, offer acceptable performance.
Soon | NTU: Is the accuracy very good enough so that we can deploy our model into our production environment?
Soon | NTU: to do the, like, prediction, right? So…
Soon | NTU: Let's take a look at the…
Soon | NTU: performance metrics here, right? If I run it.
Soon | NTU: And then I get a confusion matrix of 93, 4, and 103.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so all these metrics, classification metrics are already computed here, okay? So, basically, we are only displaying the value here, okay? So what do we have?
Soon | NTU: 0.96, you mean 96%, accuracy, 97%, precision, 96% recall, 96…
Soon | NTU: All are above 0.95, 95%. So, is this a very good model?
Soon | NTU: I think it's quite okay, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so I think it is a very well-balanced model, classification model.
Soon | NTU: Based on the classification, so-called the metrics that we have obtained here.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so now, if you look at this, right, just so we know what is this 90?
Soon | NTU: Anyone can still recall.
Soon | NTU: I, I, I know, I know them…
Soon | NTU: I know the confusion metrics is,
Soon | NTU: Anyone can tell me what is IT?
Jagatheeswaran Rajagurunathan: more positive.
Jagatheeswaran Rajagurunathan: Through Buster.
Soon | NTU: true positive. True negative.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Thief.
Soon | NTU: True negative, yes.
Soon | NTU: Right, in the web, okay? Yeah. Usually…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: 03 is true positive.
Soon | NTU: So, we have to be careful. Okay, so scikit-learn confusion metrics, by default, the top left number is a true negative one. Okay, so let me show you. Okay, so following this diagram.
Soon | NTU: Jermaine show you also. Okay, so what we'd like to see is your true negative and true positive, the green colored cell.
Soon | NTU: To be as high as possible.
Soon | NTU: And this tool…
Soon | NTU: Type 1 error, type 2 error, you know. So, to be as low as possible, okay? So, if you look at our…
Soon | NTU: metrics for our logistic regression, right? So, out of 1,000 observations, The 200,000 anomi.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, 1000.
Soon | NTU: No, we don't have one. Okay, so this is actually based on the… Size of your test data.
Soon | NTU: Okay, 1000 is actually 4.
Soon | NTU: So we actually have about 20,000, because
Soon | NTU: 200, sorry. 200, because 20…
Soon | NTU: About 0.2, right? So it's 20% for the test data, so we have about…
Soon | NTU: 200. So 200, if you look at it, this… 92.
Soon | NTU: Negative, and 1032 positive. And the fourth prediction are only 7.
Soon | NTU: So, that is why your prediction, your classification metrics are
Soon | NTU: or above 0.95, right? So it should be considered quite good, right?
Soon | NTU: Because everything is quite, well-balanced, right?
Soon | NTU: Do you know what I mean? Right.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we have, completed the part one.
Soon | NTU: And, we have about… 0.5 seconds.
Soon | NTU: Okay, anyway, we will try to do this in another session. Is it… is it okay, Jimmy?
Soon | NTU: Oh, my…
germayne: I'm… I'm… I'm… I'm… I'm thinking…
germayne: maybe we can see if we can use Thursday
germayne: We can use Thursday to continue, and then we can just run over to Saturday.
germayne: Yeah, I think we don't need to rush, and if, let's say… let's say we don't have time for the extra activities on Saturday, then I think we can always postpone to the next one.
germayne: Yeah, but the… I think the challenge is that
germayne: We do have a few… a large number of content to cover, which are actually super important, so it's not like we can just skip… it's not like we can just skip any.
germayne: So…
germayne: I think… I think for… okay, I think maybe one… one direction we can do is we can just continue
germayne: with… it is on Thursday, then if there's any extra stuff, you'll just roll over to Saturday.
germayne: Okay? At least, that makes the learning experience more… more consistent from the curriculum perspective. Yeah, because initially, I thought we can complete everything, and I just missed out the… the metrics, but it feels like I think we… we just need to spill over lah. I think let's just do that.
germayne: Then on Saturday, we probably… I think maybe the Kaggle, we can see whether if we can stabilize towards next week. Anyway, we have a couple of weeks more, so it's fine, yeah.
germayne: Yeah, so I think, let's do that. So maybe what we can do is we will just continue on the sequence on… on Thursday, then Thursday, I'll just do as much as possible with what we can, then anything else, we just continue off from… from Saturday. So maybe soon.
germayne: can continue the notebook as it is on… on… on Thursday, yeah. Then let's just do that, lah. Then, if you've got extra time, I'll just continue, yeah.
Soon | NTU: We'd rather, you know.
germayne: Who's style.
Soon | NTU: slowly, make sure everyone is, understand, rather than trying to rush through everything, okay? So, and if you have… do have questions, so you can also post it in the Discord. We're trying to, answer them, even before the class, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so I think that's one way to help to clarify some of our points, rather than, you know, we raise it during the class, and then
Soon | NTU: And then we will have to…
Soon | NTU: The time will run out very lightly.
Soon | NTU: Yeah. So…
germayne: Yeah.
Soon | NTU: Thank you.
germayne: Okay, but I think one thing to just update everyone, right? So I think a lot of it is on the API side, which I personally don't think is…
germayne: is…
germayne: like, really that important, because actually the code and the API you guys can explore. So I think the takeaway should be, conceptually.
germayne: that you understand why if some… like, I think just now some of you guys mentioned, like, oh, you know, the scaling is not good, I should not use it. I'm quite scared that you guys go with that conclusion, because I don't think that's what I said.
germayne: So… so I think those are quite fundamentally important to know when to use something. So if you don't know, then I think you have to ask us again.
germayne: And even if I say it depends, right, then just keep asking, you just keep asking, until you get the right answer. But it shouldn't be that the takeaway is that, oh, you know, this is not good, therefore I don't use. I don't think that is the conclusion that we are saying. I think there are some stuff I didn't agree that I explicitly called out, but I believe, let's say, for the pre-processing, it is a must-do.
germayne: But the takeaway should be when I should do it. It shouldn't be that, oh, it's not good, I don't do it. I don't think that's the case, yeah?
germayne: Yeah, so just be, just be aware of that lah, yeah.
Easwaran Jayaraman: I'm sorry, may I drop off? I need to…
germayne: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, okay, yeah, then I'll see you guys.
Easwaran Jayaraman: drop me off.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, no problems. I'll see you guys on Thursday. Then, what, for the rest, let's… let's do the… let's do the…
Chieh Cheng Lai: Oi.
germayne: Sorry?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Is this a way?
germayne: Yes, yes, yes. Yes, yes, yes, we need. Yeah, let me, let me open up, give me a while.
germayne: Okay, so just let me share… really bald.
Soon | NTU: Continue to part 2, 3 on the Thursday.
germayne: Yeah, we will continue… we continue that. Then I'll… then after that, once we're done, then I'll continue… I'll continue with the… the lesson.
germayne: Okay, but the content is just a lot lah, and I don't think it's,
germayne: I don't think it's anybody's fault, it's just that we have to squeeze in… this, basically, this is like…
germayne: This is, like, this is 3.3, right? Okay.
germayne: Yeah, but basically, we are squeezing in a portion of a, like, a machine learning module, to be honest.
germayne: Let me share my screen.
germayne: Is he?
germayne: Yeah, so, understandable that we are just trying to squeeze a lot of concept.
germayne: Okay, why is my screen not moving?
germayne: Sorry,
germayne: Okay.
germayne: So, what is the takeaway for today that is important? What are the things that you guys learned?
germayne: Matrix, yep.
germayne: Yep.
germayne: Yeah, all your confusion matrix, End quote, confused.
germayne: I think… I think, I think it will be helpful for you guys to have more hands-on, so hopefully the Kaggle will be a good, will be a good approach.
germayne: Alright? I think you guys need to try.
germayne: And then I think it will… it will help to…
germayne: Emphasize on when we should be using what.
germayne: Yeah, okay, we will… we will continue with the regression metrics on Thursday.
germayne: Yeah?
germayne: Okay, so which part so far today is the most challenging?
germayne: Hey, wait, are you guys able to…
germayne: Okay, so which part do you guys find easier?
germayne: Oh, okay, oh, so some… okay, so some people, I think, maybe… Okay, the thing here is that if you have personally asked… if you have, like, came across all these, right, then I think maybe it will be easier. If it's the first time that you are seeing all these, then obviously it will be very challenging, because we are basically squeezing the
germayne: almost, like, I would say almost to some extent, a…
germayne: a whole module worth of concept in, like, what, 6 hours? It's just really very challenging. Even with 79 hours, it's still very tough, to be honest.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: So suddenly they will find everything.
germayne: Maybe after the end of the class, I will ask you guys if you guys think Module 2 is harder, or Module 3 is harder.
germayne: Or maybe difficult in its own ways, huh?
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Everything.
germayne: You guys feel everything challenging?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I feel that, some of the things, like, like, like, I thought I knew, but then…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Today, like, like, a lot more things I didn't know.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Oh, that's why it's, like, everything.
germayne: Okay, the thing here is that you guys…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: It's like we read about ML, about this, about that. Yo, I thought,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Now, like, for example, like, I just read the question, right, that, oh, applying the scaling on the Y. Wow, is it that interesting? I never thought of that. Yeah, so… I thought I was really blind, like, what Jack said, mind blown.
germayne: Yeah, so that they…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: What do you do with it, man? Correct.
germayne: Right, so the thing here is I will tend to give you guys more insight that usually I don't think you can find, right? Because if I'm just going to tell you, like, the very basic surface stuff, right, then I don't think it's difficult. But probably you won't really understand, I think.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, so it's like, so it seems like there's a, there's, there's no,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Y equals to, you know, equals X plus 1, kind of, you know, then, yeah, you know, they just fit in, but it seems like you can play around with it almost everywhere, so this is my confusion, that's like…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: This is what to write. Sorry.
germayne: Okay, yeah, no problem, no problem. I think, I think just continue to ask.
germayne: Or too slower.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Oh, that's why you can… from me, I answer all the… I asked all the funny questions once, like…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, I mean, I thought just one method, take anything and run, you know, you don't really have time to think about this, about that, but now you're like, oh, this is, like, that's not… that's not… that's not good.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: In fact, that's wrong. Say, okay, that's interesting, okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
germayne: Okay, I think, I think we are slow lah, for sure, for sure, I think.
germayne: But I think probably this is a good place lah. This is a good place.
germayne: To explain a bit more, rather than rushing.
germayne: Yeah, because I think these are all important, though. I mean, if it's… if it's not important, usually I'll try to skip, but I feel like all these concepts are just… I… basically, what we go through today is just foundation ML. Some… if your goal is very motivated to do data science, some of these really will be tested.
germayne: It will be tested, like, you need to know all this.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, so it's actually quite split lah. Some people think a bit slow, some, about one-third thing is okay.
germayne: Okay, so I think it's a bit tight between… it's too fast. I think we are… I think the thing here is that you can see we can't even finish it in 3 hours.
germayne: And we had to spill over, so…
germayne: Yeah, if you can't go any slower, man.
germayne: Yeah, but we will see what we can spill over on Saturday lah, if possible.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, but I like it, I mean, I just wonder, is it just really everything? So it's like, oh, yeah. I think…
germayne: I think that's why I think end of Module 3, I'll ask you guys if you guys think this is harder, or Module 2 is harder.
germayne: Right? I think I told you guys, right, this one is a bit different. It's challenging in a different way.
germayne: Yeah?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Hmm.
germayne: Okay, so what do you guys think is good? What was a good takeaway for you guys today?
germayne: What are the… what are the things that you felt like, you know?
germayne: Interesting.
germayne: And you didn't expect?
Jagatheeswaran Rajagurunathan: January?
germayne: Yes, yep.
Jagatheeswaran Rajagurunathan: If, I think it'll be quite difficult for the rest, but, I mean, for me, it's okay if you want to, like, start half an hour earlier.
Jagatheeswaran Rajagurunathan: Rather than push at the end.
Jagatheeswaran Rajagurunathan: So we don't miss out.
germayne: Okay, I think… I think maybe what I can do is to just start at 7.
germayne: Not sure if it will help.
germayne: Yeah, I don't think it's possible to start earlier lah. I mean, a lot of people have work timing, so…
germayne: Yeah, I think it's okay, it's okay. Let's… let's see if we can try to start on Saturday on time. So maybe what you guys can do is, we'll try to start on time on Saturday, so we'll start sharply at 9.
germayne: Given that there's still a lot of content.
germayne: Alright? Yeah, I'll try my best to do it on Saturday lah. And maybe we can spill a bit…
germayne: On Saturday.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, I think it's good to know that it's a lot to learn. There's just a lot, there's just way too many things to be covered in the class.
germayne: And… and I think you guys know my style so far, that there's actually a lot of nuance. I don't like to do very surface intro… I think if you do very surface, it's very easy, right? Or, you know, this metric is just like that. Yeah, so it's good that you guys realize that there's actually a lot of small nuance.
germayne: And… basically, you should start to see a lot of things linking to each other. Yeah, I think that's a good thing.
germayne: Okay, so I'll go to the next. Okay, so what are some of the areas you feel like you can improve on based on today?
germayne: I think, as you guys write, I think don't be too worried too much about machine learning module. The good thing I would say, about machine learning is that
germayne: the resources to read this is very accessible. You can easily just find everybody reading this, you should find different variations of people's blog, you should find different variation of a lot of concepts, so…
germayne: I would say the accessibility, as compared to Module 2, is more… is more accessible, which is why I think I… I try to… I try to emphasize concepts that you won't find outside, usually, and I want you guys to note it down. But if it's, like.
germayne: you know, like, how is a metric calculated? Those, usually, you can find it. Which is why I say for the code, right?
germayne: the code. That is even easier, you can find it everywhere, a lot, there will be a lot of examples. So, good news from Module 3 is
germayne: Easy to assess it.
germayne: But…
germayne: might not be able to find some of the nuance or danger misconception that people might have, so I think that is what you guys should take note.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, I don't think you guys need to worry about practicing. We will have the keger to… to practice. You will definitely have a good exposure on the Kaggle competition that we will do in the class.
germayne: Huh?
germayne: Yeah, okay, so I think that's all for today. I think, we exceeded by a bit, but yeah, I think let's not, let's not, let's not…
germayne: I think let's… let's call it a day, and we'll come back on… on Thursday, okay? If you guys have got any questions for now, maybe you can stay back and just ask, but for the rest, yeah, thank you for… thank you for today. I think it's a long… it's really a lot of content. We've still got a lot more to cover on Thursday.
germayne: But, yeah, I will see you guys again on Thursday. Alright, have a good… have a good night, everybody.
germayne: Yeah, have an early night. Yep, goodbye.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Thank you for that.
germayne: Yeah, thank you so much, thank you so much, yeah.
Soon | NTU: Naiveon.
germayne: Good night, good night.
Teng Lee LIM: Thank you, good night. Bye.